<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.0/excerpt/"	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.0/"><channel>	<title>Gordon Diggs - Blog</title>	<link></link>	<description>Programming, Cooking, Life and more</description>	<pubDate>Thu Sep 22 08:43:43 -0700 2011</pubDate>	<generator>http://posterous.com</generator>	<language>en</language>	<wp:wxr_version>1.0</wp:wxr_version>	<wp:base_site_url>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com</wp:base_site_url>	<wp:base_blog_url>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com</wp:base_blog_url>		<image>		<url>http://files.posterous.com/user_profile_pics/1491936/gordon_computer_square.jpg</url>		<title>Gordon Diggs - Blog</title>		<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com</link>	</image>	<item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 0+1: Getting There and Being Here</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-0-getting-there-and-being-here</link>	<pubDate>Sat May 26 04:00:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-0-getting-there-and-being-here</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's hard to call this a day. May 24 and 25 sort of mixed together, a result of traveling across time zones, and sleeping in a plane. The journey began at JFK airport. My flight, intended to leave at 7:55pm, ended up being delayed due to a thunderstorm. I think we left around 9:30. I took the opportunity to go to sleep, and was asleep when we took off. Taking off felt like going into hyperspace; it was fun.</p><p>The plane ride itself was uneventful, and the food followed suit. Most importantly, though, I arrived in Nice safely at around noon. Immigration was simple (why is it easier to get into another country than it is to return to my own?). I bought my bus pas and hopped a bus towards my hotel. The bus drove along the coast, and I began to see the beauty of Nice.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/sNP1q.jpg" alt="" /></p><p>As you can see, it was beautiful and sunny when I arrived. Sadly, that weather didn't hold up. As I was walking to find food and a grocery store from my hotel, the rain began. Whatever, no big deal. Ate an awesome pain au chocolat and picked up the following from the store:</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/3fg0L.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Mnvyq.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>These fruit things are awesome. They're basically crackers with a chewy jelly inside. I'm keeping them in my bag for snacks. I've never had the 2 beers on the left before (tasting notes forthcoming), but Chimay Blue was a must, especially considering how cheap it is here.</p><p>Dinner was (as always) unplanned. I put on a nicer shirt and wandered out into the night. My normal tricks for finding restaurants didn't seem to work, though I think I might have been in the wrong part of town. Eventually, I came across La Maison Bleue on rue priv&eacute;e Meyerbeer. Apparently, the foie gras ravioli is incredible, though I didn't try it (may have to go back for it). Here's what I ate. The restaurant serves wine from a local vineyard, which I had, and it was awesome.</p><p><em>First course: Salade de la Mer</em></p><p>This is just as it sounds, a salade comprised of different things from the sea. If I remember correctly, it was mussels, calimari, shrimp, and maybe something else, too. They were all cooked fairly simply and were super tasty.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/6HFfh.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Second course: Filet de daurade r&ocirc;ti &agrave; la proven&ccedil;ale</em></p><p>I'd never had sea bream before. It's very tasty, kind of like sole, but with a tuna consistency. The lemon was a nice complement, and the sauce was incredible.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/OWTHJ.jpg" alt="" /></p><p><em>Third course: tarte de pomme</em></p><p>A perfect end to an amazing meal. This was as good as it looks, especially the cr&egrave;me anglaise</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/URdIV.jpg" alt="" /></p><p>After dinner, I wandered back along the promenade to my hotel, full of great food, and really glad to be in Nice. I was exhausted and passed out watching France 2. Two days, rolled into one: a great start to the trip.</p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[It's hard to call this a day. May 24 and 25 sort of mixed together, a result of traveling across time zones, and sleeping in a plane. The journey began at JFK airport. My flight, intended to leave at 7:55pm, ended up being delayed due to a thunder...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Sat May 26 04:00:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sat May 26 04:00:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>133681085</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-0-getting-there-and-being-here</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 8: My Own Monte Carlo Grand Prix</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-8-my-own-monte-carlo-grand-prix</link>	<pubDate>Sat Jun 02 00:13:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-8-my-own-monte-carlo-grand-prix</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a thing for small countries - I think it's interesting that in today's world, where a few huge countries control most everything, there are still tiny countries that can thrive on their own. So, when I found out how close Monaco was to Nice, I knew I needed to go (someday, I'll find a way into Andorra). Seriously, it takes less time and costs about the same to from Nice to Monaco round trip as it does to go from Grand Central to Wantagh in Long Island.</p><p>But before the voyage, I needed sustinance. I went back to the Italian festival on my way out to sample the porchetta sandwich, served on focaccia with some olive oil. It was super tasty. I also picked up an iced tea flavored with mango and pineapple. Seriously, why does Europe get all these cool iced tea flavors?</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/RDXCS.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>The train ride to Monaco is beautiful, since it goes right along the coast. The scenery isn't all that different than in Nice, but it's still pretty, even if it was somewhat overcast. Once in Monaco, I realized that it is the epitome of a town built into a mountain. Nice is also built into a mountain, but it's a more gradual one; Monte Carlo is basically a series of cliffs they built a city on. That makes navigation a bit difficult, since you can't really see very far in either direction, and maps aren't a huge help since often times where you want to go is on a different elevation, and you can't just jump off a cliff. Perhaps because of this, they have these really awesome signs that point out the way to walk for certain landmarks, museums, etc. They also note the nearest defribillator, which is good if you suddenly find yourself dying while wandering around Monte Carlo (in all seriousness, I'm sure the signs have saved some lives). I came out of the train station in kind of a weird spot, but began walking down some of the many stairs to hopefully find either wifi or a sign of direction. I finally found my way and came across the big market in Monaco, which features lots of local specialties for sale and consumption. Sadly, everything was closed, I think for the lunch hour, so I didn't get to see much of it. Then, I decided I would head towards the Prince's Palace and the Oceanographic museum, both of which were up this big set of stairs. From a strategic perspective, I'd say the palace is pretty safe.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/CaZCn.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>At the top, I found the palace, and this pretty view.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/gEyld.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/IsDfN.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>I decided to do the tour of the Prince's Palace. Sadly, no photos were allowed inside (and I wasn't about to argue with the soldiers with guns about that point), but the guided audiotour was really cool. You go through a somewhat small part of the palace, but you get to see interesting rooms like Louis XV's bedroom, the courtyard with the big double helix stairs carved out of one solid piece of marble, and the throne room. You also get to hear about the ceremonial usage of each room that you're in and about the origins of many of the objects in the rooms. Fun fact: there's a large cistern under the courtyard of the palace that was built to collect rainwater so that it could supply water to the city in the case of a seige.</p><p>After the palace, while heading towards the oceanographic museum, I found the Saint Nicholas Cathedral. Inside is buried a number of former Monaco monarchs.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/5H0QU.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After visiting the cathedral, I found myself at the Mus&eacute;e Oceanographique de Monaco. I have to say, this is one of the coolest museums I've ever visited. It's part art museum, part natural history museum, part panoramic viewing center, all with a sizeable aquarium at the bottom. They have preserved animals, old equipment, and some surpisignly shocking art pieces. The best part is that they are all intermixed, which throws you into this strange unbalance and is, in its own way, lots of fun. It's fun for the whole family, all at once! I also learned a lot, like that there are both seals and lobsters in the Mediterranean Sea, and the lobsters are huge. At the top of the museum, on the roof, is a scenic overlook, a museum, a playground and a turtle exhibit.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2H6Z5.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/7La90.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/og7gv.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/OuTCA.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/SMBgi.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/uDOu9.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/7UoaO.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>On my way to the Monte Carlo Casino, my last stop in Monaco, I stopped into the Jardin Saint-Martin, a botanical garden built onto a cliff. They have flowers, trees, statues, and a nice fountain, as well as incredible views of the port and coastline.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/hq1ZQ.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/jSBzK.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>I then found my way through the streets of Monte Carlo to the casino. The grand prix was less than a week ago, so understandably the city is not entirely cleaned up. A lot of the stands and barriers are still in place. It was weird knowing that right next to where I was walking, they raced cars.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/CaaIb.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/jMrmq.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>Around the casino, the streets are lined with high-end shops (Cartier, Armani, Ferragamo, etc.). The casino itself allows visitors into the lobby (no pictures, though). In order to get into the casino, you need to follow the strict dress code and pay admission. I was content to just be across the street, so didn't even bother going into the lobby. Casinos aren't really my thing; I'm not a huge gambler and so I don't really have any interest in it. The building was very pretty, though.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/d1btf.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>Now completely exhausted from the hiking and the sweating, I sat down in the park for half an hour to relax before heading back to Nice. I got lucky in that a train was leaving shortly after I arrived, so I got back to my hotel fairly quickly. For dinner, I decided I wanted pizza. I had wanted to try pizza in Monaco, given the Grimaldi history there and its relevance to my high school years in Brooklyn Heights, but I was quite tired and didn't feel like hanging around for a few more hours until dinner. Next time for sure. Back in Nice, I stopped at Attimi, a more modern restaurant near my hotel. Attimi prides itself on using locally-sourced, fresh ingredients for its dishes. I saw smoked swordfish on the menu, and had to have it, since I love swordfish and had never seen it smoked before. It was definitely fishy, but very tasty. I also got to have olive oil spiced with pimentos, which I love (and now that I know which kind of pepper they use, I can make it at home).</p><p><em>First Course: Pizza espadon fum&eacute;e (smoked swordfish)</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/YYMYy.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Sorry some is missing. I was really hungry and forgot to take a picture before I started.</p><p><em>Dessert: Mo&euml;lleux chocolat</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/uRk9q.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>I also, as usual, drank the house red, which was local and incredible. I'm really glad I've found a region of wines that I like, since I have, before this trip, never really enjoyed drinking wine.</p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I have a thing for small countries - I think it's interesting that in today's world, where a few huge countries control most everything, there are still tiny countries that can thrive on their own. So, when I found out how close Monaco was to Nice...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Sat Jun 02 00:13:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sat Jun 02 00:13:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>135385520</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-8-my-own-monte-carlo-grand-prix</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 3: Sourriez, vous êtes à Cannes!</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-3-sourriez-vous-etes-a-cannes</link>	<pubDate>Mon May 28 07:01:56 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-3-sourriez-vous-etes-a-cannes</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today was the last day of the Cannes film festival (and the Grand Prix in Monte Carlo, more on that later). I decided to hop the train over to Cannes to check it out. You can't just go watch movie screenings, since the festival is an accredited affair, but there's lots of things happening to see. I got to the train station and got my tickets, and saw that I had about an hour to kill. There wasn't much to do around the Nice-Ville station, so I went and had a coffee. There was insanity among the people trying to get to Monaco. Never in my life have I seen so many well-dressed people so frantic all at the same time. This is exactly why I'm waiting to head over to Monaco, I want to let all the craziness of the Grand Prix pass, and also be able to walk in the streets, which is hard to do when there are cars racing in them.</p><p>Before all that, though, was breakfast. I found this spot in Vieux Nice. If you've never had a croissant choc amande, you've never lived. It is definitely my favorite French pastry. I didn't take a picture, but here's the place. I always have fun just looking at all the breads and pastries, there's a certain level of skill inherent in all their creations that is just impressive.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ZJIb8.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>Ok, back to the journey to Cannes. Here's the Nice train station:</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/h960J.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/hh5Zp.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>The train ride to Cannes is interesting - not the prettiest of trips, but it's fun to see the landscape. Arriving in Cannes, I followed the crowd (of mostly Americans and Brits) towards the festival grounds. There's a little carnival-like thing on the grounds, as well as a few expensive gift shops. The red carpet is big! I'm not sure how big I expected it to be, but it was definitely larger than I imagined. The press has to stay across the street when there are events going on, and they all have these ladders they stand on to get a better view. It looked like there were some press spots along the red carpet as well, though I'm not sure how it's decided who is where.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/CzIV9.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/RRRiz.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After this, it was lunch time. I headed into the little streets of Cannes, which are just lined with little shops. It reminded me of cities in Spain. A lot of places were closed because it is Sunday, but it was still nice. I had a sandwich in a good spot. It was basically a whole baguette filled with ham, cheese and accoutrements.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/n0Pto.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>I'm not sure what it is about big hills that just make me want to prove I can get to the top, maybe it's all that time at Lehigh, but I found another hill and just had to climb it. At the top, I found the Cathedral d'Antibes. Sadly, the inside is under construction, and there's not much to see, but I checked out the Mus&eacute;e de la Caste, which is up there, too. it features pieces from cultures throughout history and was small, but fun. The views from up there were incredbile as well.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2WwxI.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/s5SaW.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/v1vhe.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>At the museum, there is this old guardtower that they used to use as a vantage point to spot attackers from miles away. It's the kind of thing that you always hear about, or see in movies, but it was really cool to see one in person, even if it wasn't the most visually striking structure. I considered climbing it, but remembered my bout with my fear of heights from yesterday, and used my better judgement.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/JiGbC.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>I also found this fearless sea gull standing around, probably trying to get food from some tourists, and was able to get pretty close. I took pictures as I got closer, in case the thing flew away, and now I have almost 10 pictures, each with the bird a little larger. Good use of memory, there.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ZlWnP.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After some more wandering in Cannes, I was tired, and it was starting to rain, so I decided it was time to head back to Nice. I got to the SNCF station, and found out the 1:05 train was delayed 4 hours (typical SNCF, huh?). Lucky for me, it was almost 5:00, so it kind of worked out well. Then, when the train arrived, it was only two cars. So, 4 train loads of us loaded into a fraction of a train. It was pretty tight, but I managed to get a seat about halfway back to Nice.</p><p>I changed and headed out to dinner. I happened upon L'Escalinda. This is the kind of restaurant I've been looking for since I got to Nice. It's tiny, packed full of tables, and crowded. The staff is a bunch of guys all having a good time, laughing, yelling to each other, and playing little tricks on the patrons. For example, they have this big bowl of chickpeas and onions that they bring from table to table, but they make it seem like the whole bowl is part of the meal. The waiters yell to the bartender for drinks and he serves them quickly. The kitchen is upstairs, and the waiters constantly talk to and laugh with the chef over an intercom. There is no dessert menu, just some prepared desserts that you can pick from (and they all look amazing). I was absolutely stuffed at the end of the meal. And the food is increcible. Here's what I had:</p><p><em>First course: Panach&eacute; de Beignets</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/m8J38.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Second course: Boulettes de viandes &agrave; la ni&ccedil;oise et gnocchi</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/KVVOT.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Dessert: Tarte au citron meringu&eacute;e</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Nrp3p.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Today was the last day of the Cannes film festival (and the Grand Prix in Monte Carlo, more on that later). I decided to hop the train over to Cannes to check it out. You can't just go watch movie screenings, since the festival is an accredited af...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Mon May 28 07:01:56 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Mon May 28 07:01:56 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>134126490</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-3-sourriez-vous-etes-a-cannes</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>I put together some furniture</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/i-put-together-some-furniture</link>	<pubDate>Mon Jul 09 06:00:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>			<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/i-put-together-some-furniture</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just moved into my new place, which meant putting together a lot of IKEA furniture, so I made a time lapse of it! Check it out:</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/BoHteXTJ65Q" frameborder="0" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I just moved into my new place, which meant putting together a lot of IKEA furniture, so I made a time lapse of it! Check it out:]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Mon Jul 09 06:00:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Mon Jul 09 06:00:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>144763403</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>i-put-together-some-furniture</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 2: Vieux Nice</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-2-vieux-nice</link>	<pubDate>Sat May 26 15:09:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-2-vieux-nice</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I came up with a name today for how I travel: accidental tourism (not to be confused with <em>The Accidental Tourist</em>). Really, this is what I do. I wander around and happen upon tourist attractions and visit them. The result of this is that my day becomes more focused on the journey, rather than the destination, since I usually don't have any idea where I'm going. I do pick destinations sometimes, but usually I just pick a direction and walk. It's pretty fun.</p><p>I started today in a search for breakfast. My hotel offers breakfast, but at 12&euro; a day, I figured I could do better. Ended up having a croissant amande and espresso. A great start to the day. While finding somewhere to sit and enjoy my croissant, I found this book market:</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/wm6Bp.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>Lots of bandes desin&eacute;es and other French books. It was fun to look around (and actually see some books I've read!). The journey of today was in Vieux Nice. It's a touristy part of town, but there are lots of shops and markets and it's fun to look around and see things. Also, I love tiny, winding streets, and it has lots of them. The next market I found was the somewhat famous market at Cours Selaya. It featured plants, fruits, cheeses, meats, and other beautiful things that came from the earth. I sort of breezed through it, so I need to revisit. Two things that stood out were these giant stalks of lavendar and this awesome spice cart. More on this when I revisit:</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/SReJV.jpg" alt="" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/FYuA3.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>Next, I headed over to the Mus&eacute;e de l'Art Moderne et l'Art Contemporaine (MAMAC). Entrance was free, which is pretty cool, and it was fun. Their current exhibition was kind of boring, but it might just be that I have a hard time getting behind 20 pieces titled "Object hung from the ceiling". I really liked the deconstruction in the pieces by Arman and the references to older art in the pieces of Yves Klein. Also, the room by Ben was totally awesome (I considered titling this post "Comment savoir si c'est de l'art ou pas?"). It reminded me of the whole punk/not punk debate, and how all that is totally useless at the end of the day. I thought the roof gallery was cool, and the views were amazing, but my fear of heights kicked in and I had to rush through them to get back inside.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ItDcf.jpg" alt="" /><br />Entrance to MAMAC (with a Calder sculpture to the left)</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/yfRfL.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Room by Ben</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/kZmEC.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />View from the top of the museum</p><p>After the museum, it was lunch time. I came across this pizza place which I stupidly didn't write down the name of it, but the pizza was good. It had olives, mushrooms and ham. Drank lots of water to stay hydrated (though bi&egrave;re pression is always so tempting). The people at the pizza place were super friendly, so I talked to them as I ate.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/oP8EW.jpg" alt="" /></p><p>After lunch, I noticed a lot of roads were going uphill, and that I could see some form of mountainous thing at the top of them. So, it became my goal to get to the top. What I later realized is that I had arrived at Lou Cast&egrave;u, an old park/waterfall/church on top of the big hill. It seems that in the 18th and 19th centuries, they re-constructed these structures from the middle ages, so they still stand. And there was a waterfall. It was a lot of fun, and the views were amazing. I got sweaty.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ku7mr.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />challenge accepted.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/RgMlv.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br /><span style="text-decoration: line-through;">Old pile of rocks</span> Roman ruins of a 12th century cathedral</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/EbCAL.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Waterfall! The mist was really refreshing</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/IhBtY.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />The view of Nice from the top</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ChdKx.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Me trying to look cool, but really just being sweaty.</p><p>I traveled back along the beach to my hotel, bathed, relaxed, and got ready for dinner. I wanted to go to Lou Pistou to have their tripes &agrave; la ni&ccedil;oise, but they are closed until Monday, so I shall return then and get my innards on. I wandered more through Vieux Nice for something good. I happened upon Le Maquis, intrigued by their Delices Ni&ccedil;ois, since I want to try a lot of local things.</p><p><em>First Course: Delices Ni&ccedil;ois (petits farcis ni&ccedil;ois and poivrons &agrave; l'huile)</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/El1fS.jpg" alt="" /></p><p><em>Second Course: C&ocirc;t&eacute; de Porc po&ecirc;l&eacute;e &agrave; la Myrte</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/FQMlg.jpg" alt="" /></p><p><em>Dessert: Cr&egrave;me Brul&eacute;e</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/oyFfV.jpg" alt="" /></p><p>Tomorrow, I'm off to Cannes for the last day of the festival, and to wander there!</p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I came up with a name today for how I travel: accidental tourism (not to be confused with The Accidental Tourist). Really, this is what I do. I wander around and happen upon tourist attractions and visit them. The result of this is that my day bec...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Sat May 26 15:09:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sat May 26 15:09:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>133800789</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-2-vieux-nice</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 10: Bonne Fête, Maman!</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-10-bonne-fete-maman</link>	<pubDate>Sun Jun 03 15:12:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-10-bonne-fete-maman</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today is Mother's Day in France. Interestingly, Father's Day is the same date as in the US, and it sort of works since they're so close together. The day here is absolutely joyous. Similar to how everyone congratulated other couples on their wedding days, everyone says "Bonne F&ecirc;te" to any mother they see during the day. Flowers also play a big part in the day. Mothers receive and carry roses and bouquets all day. Lots of restaurants not normally open on Sundays were open for brunch or lunch today.</p><p>My own day began in Vieux Nice, as I returned to the pastry shop I've visited a few times to grab a croissant amande for the day. I also bought breakfast for tomorrow, since I won't have time to pick it up before I head to the airport. I had my croissant and a coffee in Place du Palais.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/QH3JK.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After this bit of fortification, I headed to the Th&eacute;atre de la Photographie et de l'Image, a museum of photographs. The current exhibit is of photos by Brass&iuml;. I felt kind of strange taking photos of photos, but I snapped a shot of one of the rooms to capture the general feel of the museum. The front room of the museum is dedicated to the history of the camera, with camera from throughout the centuries on display. The photos of Brassa&iuml; were incredible. They had a unique way of sucking you in and making you feel like you were really there. He depicted France in the early 20th century, specifically Paris and Nice between the two world wars. I look at art much more quickly than most people, but I was driven to take my time more with these photos. One of Brassa&iuml;'s quotes, printed on the wall, matched my feelings of Nice pretty well: "Nice et ses environs sont d'une fabuleuse beaut&eacute; m&ecirc;me par temps maussade. Le paradis devait avoir le m&ecirc;me aspect." / "Nice and its surroundings have a certain fantastic beauty, even in dull times. Paradise must have had the same aspect."</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/8KPoe.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/IMmMo.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/PVndE.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>Part of the last day of a vacation is doing as many things that you know you want to do, but haven't had a chance to yet. My big one was eating a cr&egrave;pe, since they are one of my favorite French foods. In Paris, cr&egrave;pes are available at nearly every corner. In Nice, it's a bit more difficult to find one, and even more so to find savory cr&egrave;pes. Regardless, I knew where I had seen them, so I acquired one and sat on a bench by the beach to enjoy it.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/CYFVa.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>On my way out of the photography exhibit, I had looked at the rack of brochures to see if there was anything else interesting I could check out, since I didn't have much planned for today. I found out that the gardens at Villa Arson were open today, and it was the last day of the three day exhibit. I had no idea what Villa Arson was, nor where it was, but that made me want to go check it out even more. I found out the address and took the tram north, almost to the end of the line. I think the area I was in is technically a part of Cimiez, the next town north of Nice (though it's all connected and there is no real division). The area is very quiet and residential. I would never have had any other reason to be up there if it weren't for this exhibit. The tiny streets of the area are lined with old villas, a stark constrast to the apartment buildings and hotels of southern Nice. As I walked the nearly deserted streets to the exhibit, I could smell Mothers' Day meals cooking, including the wonderful smell of fresh bread that wafted through the streets.</p><p>When I arrived at Villa Arson (which, by the way, is on top of yet another giant hill), I found out it is an art institute for contemporary art. Built on the site of an old villa, the institution also maintains a garden of non-native plants, such as palms from Senegal, and aloe and acacia plants. The free (as in beer and as in that there is no guide) tour takes you throught the garden, the institute, and the terraces, which offer great overlooks of Nice. There are also a number of installations done by former students of the institute. My favorite was Felice Varini's "Quatre points de vue" which was a three dimensional painting that created a circle from shapes painted on various surfaces when viewed from the right position. The terraces also hold a number of amphitheaters, where I believe classes can be held.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/F16UZ.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/xJw17.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/8WKUC.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/pn1OP.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/CLIxX.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/fZbqg.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>I headed back to my hotel briefly to check in to my flight and print my boarding pass, then headed back out to the Mus&eacute;e des Beaux-Arts, which is a little bit further west of the Mus&eacute;e Massena. On the way, I saw a band playing a show in a gazebo in the park. I listened for a moment, but wasn't impressed. The museum is inside an old mansion, and features art from the 16th to 20th centuries. Not my favorite styles, but I was impressed by the sheer size of some of the paintings (entire walls) and also liked the works by Gustav-Adolf Mossa, a painter from Nice. I, in a way, enjoyed the building more than the art, though I was baffled why it appeared that someone had painted white over murals on many of the walls. I also enjoyed this sculpture by Anonyme (amazing that s/he had time to sculpt after writing so many poems and hymns and painting so many pieces, right?) because it managed to really make it appear there was a veil over the face of the woman. After visiting the museum, and its small garden outside, I walked back along the beach, pausing to watch some brave souls parasail, which I could and would never do. I also drank a can of this carbonated iced tea, which was much better than I expected it to be. It pays to be adventurous!</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/nthVG.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/26vtC.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/TezoD.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/TtudP.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/mR2Yk.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/D7djZ.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>For dinner, I came upon &nbsp;La Taca d'Oli. I started with a salad with warm ch&egrave;vre. I considered having the farcis, but knew as soon as the salad came that I had made the right decision. I hadn't had steak at all since arriving in Nice, so I had some tonight. One thing they never teach you in a French education is about how to order meat at different temperatures. All I've ever known is "bleu," which is basically just cooked long enough to sear each side (if even that) and "medium" which is comparable to an American medium-rare. Tonight I learned "rouge" from the waiter, who was very confused as to why we call steak "rare," which was a little rarer than you might find in the states if you ordered the steak rare. It was incredibly tasty. The steak itself was grilled with herbes de Provence, which I would not have thought to add to a steak, but the earthiness of the herbs complemented the steak flavor perfectly. The french fries were served with super spicy mustard, which was great. For dessert, I tried the Ile flottante, which is meringue floating in cr&egrave;me anglaise (it actually floats, too!). It was basically just sugar in a bowl, but there's nothing wrong with that every once in a while.</p><p><em>First Course: Salade de ch&egrave;vre chaud</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/FD7QV.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Second Course: Noix d'entrec&ocirc;te grill&eacute;e aux herbes de Provence</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/aRb2x.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Dessert: Ile flottante</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/obSNY.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>Whenever I travel, right around day 9 or so I start to get ansy and ready to go home. I think it's the way that I travel; I get tired of the unkown and the wandering. It set in a little bit yesterday, and a little more today. So, I took some time after dinner to walk around and say goodbye to the town I've come to love, the streets I've come to know. I walked along the promenade, looking out at the city all lit up, remembering when I went where, what I did, and how much fun I had. It occurred to me that this trip has been everything I had wanted it to be, and I would do it all again in an instant. Nevertheless, I am ready to go home, back to NYC, back to cellular data and reliable wifi. Back to texting and talking on the phone. Back to being in the same time zone as everyone else I know and back to not walking miles and miles every day. I think a part of any vacation is being reminded of what you have waiting upon your return, and, at least for a short time, having a renewed appreciation for that. But the most important thing to take away from a vacation is memories, and I have tons of those. Luckily, they don't add weight to my suitcase.</p><p>Au revoir, Nice. A bientot. Je t'aime.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vulER.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Today is Mother's Day in France. Interestingly, Father's Day is the same date as in the US, and it sort of works since they're so close together. The day here is absolutely joyous. Similar to how everyone congratulated other couples on their weddi...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Sun Jun 03 15:12:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sun Jun 03 15:12:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>135739479</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-10-bonne-fete-maman</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 6: Old Things and Extravagant Dining</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-6-old-things-and-extravagant-di</link>	<pubDate>Thu May 31 03:14:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-6-old-things-and-extravagant-di</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for the lateness of this post - the hotel wifi wasn't working last night. I finally found a cafe to write in. Yesterday was a day filled with old things belonging to dead people. The day began at the Mus&eacute;e d'Histoire Naturelle here in Nice. I didn't have many expectations going in, which I guess was good. This museum is <em>tiny</em>. It's really just one room of a few stuffed animals (a lot of birds) and this strange presentation (more on that soon). It was cool, though, to read about the environmental history of the area, and how the environment has changed as cities have grown. This wolf pretty much sums up the animals displayed:</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/sQjuc.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>There was also this strange diorama of two scientists who started discovering wildlife in the area. You press a button and it plays a scene of the two of them talking. The'yre not animatronic, though, there are just spot lights on whoever is talking at a given moment. The preserved animals behind them were kind of cool in a gross way, though. Also, this wasn't a short thing - I stood there for about 10 minutes watching these 2 people talk!</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/tbZFK.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After the museum, I began wandering a little bit, since I was in a new area. Nothing super exciting - it was a much less touristy area, so there were a lot of normal city things (clothing stores, grocery stores, etc.). I then headed back to that nicer shopping area I mentioned in my last post, to go see what it was all about. In doing so, I stumbled upon the Mus&eacute;e Massena.&nbsp;</p><p>The Mus&eacute;e Massena used to be a mansion of the Mass&eacute;na family, and was donated by them to become a museum in the early 20th century (just before the first World War). The chateau has been left somewhat the same - it's very extravagant as you might expect and there are big rooms with high ceilings and wall dressings. I especially liked the library and the greatroom. The upstairs is somewhat of a gallery now, and it was really cool to look at the old posters for the festivals they had in Nice. There are also depictions of Nice throughout history, and it was fun to learn about that as well. Outside the museum is a nice garden that I sat in for a while and scribbled in my notebook. Oh yeah, and entrance is free. Score.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/uHMWR.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/XK6Nr.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/qm9aF.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vVCS0.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/5e2wq.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />I've never seen a tiger like this - sad they had to kill such a rare one to become a rug, huh?</p><p>After the museum, I headed over to check out the Palais Lascaris, in Vieux Nice. This is an old palace right in the middle of everything (I've walked by it many times and completely missed it). It was converted into a museum in the 60s. The coolest part is the 18th century pharmacy that has been left entirely intact. It reminded me of a scene from <em>Sleep No More</em>. The rest of the palace is an exhibit of instruments from various years, including this funky 19th century upright piano, a cane violin, and serpents.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/YKiUC.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/T2eIa.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Osok3.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/WaDmJ.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/0cXal.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>And that brings us now to dinner. I figured, since part of this trip is to celebrate my graduation, I should go to one super nice dinner while in Nice. I chose Le Chantecler, which is nestled at the foot of Le Negresco hotel, right on the promenade. Let me give you a taste of what this restaurant is like. The waiters are all dressed in tails. All the silverware, food, drinks, and everything else is served on silver trays, with someone carrying the tray and someone serving it at the table. The dishes are all presented with covers, and all covers at a table are removed at the same time, which became fun to watch at the table next to me, with 10 people, requiring 5 waiters for every course. Among the selections on the menu is a tasting menu, where you simply sit and enjoy 7 courses selected and prepared by the chef. The Menu Chantecler is similar, but with fewer courses, and you pick the main course. I chose to do the Menu Chantecler. Both of these options can also be accompanied by a wine pairing, in case you feel like having 7 glasses of wine with dinner. In short, imagine the most extravagant, fanciest dining experience you can, and then double it. That is the experience of eating at Le Chantecler. Interestingly, the current chef is known for his modern presentations of classic dishes, which adds a subtle reminder that you are, in fact, still in the 21st century. What follows will likely be a long, absurd description, but it is such only to reflect the reality of the meal. I now present Dinner, in 15 movements:</p><ol><li>I began with the champagne cart - there were three different champagnes to choose from, and they were masterfully poured right there for you.</li><li>After the champagne, I was brought the hors d'oeuvres. They were a plate with three little selections. My favorite was the foie gras served on a small chocolate cookie.</li><li>I was then presented with, and explained, the menu. The waiter told me about the different dining options, recommended plates, etc.</li><li>After some reflection (which is the word used in French when deciding what to eat), I ordered my meal.</li><li>I was then told I would be visited next by the Somelier (it's kind of like <em>A Christmas Carol, </em>with more food). He brought me the dictionary-sized binder that is the wine list, and was available for questions while I selected.</li><li>I was then presented with the bread options, and picked the olive bread for my first piece. The butter they put at the table was incredible as well.</li><li>Next, I was brought a small bowl of soup topped with morels to, as the waiter put it, "give a taste of the chef's cuisine." It was very tasty, especially because I love morels.</li><li>Next was a soft egg yolk with green peas cream, served also with meat and salted butter.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/2AJXg.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/jQRt8.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li><li>The next dish was lobster meat, served with a red wine sauce and a few vegetables.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/LH11R.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li><li>After that, I was brought the dish I had ordered: piglet served with boudin noir, apples and lentils.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/VGaxl.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li><li>Next, I was presented with the cheese cart, and told where each of the 10 or so cheeses came from. They all looked incredible. I chose the camembert, the local ch&egrave;vre, and the roquefort. They were served with apricots, figs, and raisin bread.</li><li>I was then presented with pre-dessert. What is pre-dessert you ask? It's every child's dream, that's what it is. Pre-dessert was a biscuit and a little bit of vanilla gelato. Very tasty.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/OQkM2.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li><li>After pre-dessert, I had dessert. This was swiss chard pie, a local specialty (it is also served as a savory pie), with orange blossom cream and a bit of sorbet.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/UDQbh.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li><li>After dessert, I was presented with the coffee menu. The restaurant has about 8 different coffees to choose from, and they are all described in detail (including the type of bean and origin), with tasting notes for each.</li><li>Lastly, the after-dessert cart was brought over. This was a selection of macaroons, truffles, and other small pastries or candies to select from.</li></ol><p>After all that, I basically rolled home - there was so much food. The experience was unlike anything I've ever done, and though it was wildly expensive, you receive a lot of amazing food, and it is entirely worth it. I almost instantly passed out from from food overload and slept like a baby, even though Cypress Hill was performing just across the street from my hotel. Another great day on this great voyage.</p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Sorry for the lateness of this post - the hotel wifi wasn't working last night. I finally found a cafe to write in. Yesterday was a day filled with old things belonging to dead people. The day began at the Musée d'Histoire Naturelle here in Nice. ...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Thu May 31 03:14:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Thu May 31 03:14:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>134865262</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-6-old-things-and-extravagant-di</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 9: Curiosity, Community, and a Cat</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-9-curiosity-community-and-a-cat</link>	<pubDate>Sat Jun 02 14:22:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-9-curiosity-community-and-a-cat</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I learned last night that I'm really bad at writing post cards. I don't remember the last time I did it, and that may be why. To me, it's a weird length to write, and when I'm 8 days into a 10 day trip, how do I catch the recipient up on everything? Regardless, I managed to scrounge up enough words to form something similar to sentences and wrote my cards. This morning, I went off to the post office to send them out. The postal workers were very helpful, and also very tolerant of my sheer ignorance as to how much to pay for a stamp and where to put the cards. The woman walked over to the machine with me and walked me through everything.</p><p>On the way to the post office was one of the Hotels de Ville of Nice. And, being that it is Saturday, weddings were in full force. Weddings in France are very different than in the US. For one, they are always held in the hotel de ville of the town in which one of the spouses live, rather than in a church. Some couples choose to have a church wedding as well as the legal ceremony, but it is increasingly rare. The mayor of the town oversees the weddings and signs the marriage licenses. Anyway, every Saturday, particularly in Nice, a crowd grows outside of the Hotel de Ville to celebrate the couples as they exit - there is confetti and cheering, not just for the couples known by the people outside, but for everyone who comes out. It's a very joyous and wonderful thing to see.</p><p>After the post office, I headed towards the used book market that I visited last Saturday. It happens the third and first Saturdays of the month, so I was lucky to be here for it twice. Since I was actually looking for it this time, I was able to spend some more time there. For one, it seemed bigger this time than last week, which was cool. The other thing that I noticed as I browsed the hundreds of books, BDs and prints was that it's not just about selling and buying books, it's about discussing books, pointing out rare ones or talking about favorites. I was tempted to ask for recommendations for some BDs, but I realized that only a few of them are pretty heavy and that would be weight I'd have to carry back home.</p><p>After the market, I went on the prowl for lunch. On a whim, I decided to head towards Place Garibaldi, the location of Cave de la Tour, a (supposedly) amazing raw seafood restaurant, who raises and sells their own oysters. They look incredible, and I wish I liked oysters so that I could eat there. As I was walking, I noticed, among the sandwiches, pizza and socca, a stand was selling hot dogs. I remembered suddenly that I had wanted to try a hot dog similar to this one when I was in Paris last and never got a chance, so I jumped on the opportunity. This was essentially a different take on a croque monsieur (a sandwich that is surpassed in tastiness by its female counterpart, the croque madame, which adds a soft-yolk egg to the top). The hot dog itself was placed in a small baguette, then covered in b&eacute;chamel sauce and draped with gruy&egrave;re cheese. It was simply amazing, and I may need to replicate it at home (though the danger of how easy making b&eacute;chamel sauce is may make me gain 50 or so pounds).</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ZBoCa.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After lunch, I headed towards the Mus&eacute;e de la curiosit&eacute; et de l'insolite. I heard about this museum only after seeing a flyer for it at the Terra Amata museum a few days ago, and wasn't really all that sure what to expect. What I found is one of the most fun museums I've ever been to. The museum is at the former location of Barale, which as I learned was a famous restaurant in Nice. The museum itself features old automatic toys, animatronics, and illusions. It's run by one man, who is clearly very passionate about the subject. He's also, as evidenced by the certificate on the wall, a magician. I arrived at the same time as a small girl and her mother and we were given a tour of the seven rooms of the museum. Many things animate themselvers, others you press a button to see what they do. As part of the tour, you not only learn about object automation throughout history (going back even to the 17th and 18th centuries), but also get to see a small presentation in one of the rooms, which includes lots of cool automated events and ghosts. The owner was very excited that I was from the US (and even more excited that I was from New York), since I was the first american to visit his museum. He insisted I sign his guest book, which I gladly did. After spending some time pushing all the buttons I could, and looking at all the great toys, I headed back towards my hotel to relax in the park for a little while before dinner.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/chTJX.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/8V8px.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/VWo7D.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>For dinner, I decided to go back to C&ocirc;t&eacute; Marais, mainly to try the Andouillette, which is a tripe sausage (or meta-intestine if you prefer). The staff instantly recognized and welcomed me back, apologizing that "my table" was reserved. The wiater helped me select a wine, and I noted that as he talked to other patrons just how much he knows about the wine selection at the restaurant. The selection is not small, it's written on a two-sided 4 foot tall board, and he could describe the qualities of each in detail. I started with scallops, which I don't normally like, but these were incredibly soft (not chewy, which is how I usually find them) and flavorful. The carmelized vegetables accented the flavor well. I then had the Andouillete, which has a very unusual and differrent flavor. It was incredibly tasty, but the flavor was not one you'd normally find. It's hard to describe, and I suppose the best way is to say that it was much more evident what part of the animal you were eating than it was with the tripes &agrave; la ni&ccedil;oise. The mustard sauce with it was incredible, and definitely helped dumb down the innard flavor just enough that it was still very present, but not overpowering. For dessert, I had the Mousse au Pavot, which is a while chocolate mousse with poppy seeds in it, which created an incredible texture. The pur&eacute;ed red fruits also added a nice little boost of sweetness as well.</p><p><em>First course: Noix de Saint-Jacques po&ecirc;ll&eacute;es, Endives caramelis&eacute;e</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ABoLc.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Second course: Andouillette artisinale</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ybSTE.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Dessert: Mousse au Pavot, pur&eacute;e aux fruits rouges</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/RDq9s.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>While I was eating, a white cat appeared across the street, climbing in and out of the window as it built and lost courage to venture out. It ultimately retreated permanently back into the building.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Od6PA.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I learned last night that I'm really bad at writing post cards. I don't remember the last time I did it, and that may be why. To me, it's a weird length to write, and when I'm 8 days into a 10 day trip, how do I catch the recipient up on everythin...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Sat Jun 02 14:22:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sat Jun 02 14:22:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>135515862</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-9-curiosity-community-and-a-cat</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>			<wp:comment>			<wp:comment_id>11388804</wp:comment_id>							<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Cheap Textbooks]]></wp:comment_author>				<wp:comment_author_url><![CDATA[http://www.bookbyte.com/]]></wp:comment_author_url>						<wp:comment_date>Tue Sep 11 23:26:43 -0700 2012</wp:comment_date>			<wp:comment_date_gmt>Tue Sep 11 23:26:43 -0700 2012</wp:comment_date_gmt>			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[The blog is detailing about the task very clearly with out any confusion. The theme and the way of narration is very exiting and is very interesting to the readers of the blog.]]></wp:comment_content>			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>		</wp:comment>	</item><item>	<title>I sing a cappella. Sometimes I have solos.</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/i-sing-a-cappella-sometimes-i-have-solos</link>	<pubDate>Sun Nov 06 18:49:16 -0800 2011</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>			<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/i-sing-a-cappella-sometimes-i-have-solos</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/WAlKhZQzzoo?wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen frameborder="0" height="417" width="500"></iframe></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Sun Nov 06 18:49:16 -0800 2011</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sun Nov 06 18:49:16 -0800 2011</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>78939050</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>i-sing-a-cappella-sometimes-i-have-solos</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Orlando Record Stores Trip and Review</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/orlando-record-stores-trip-and-review</link>	<pubDate>Wed Mar 07 15:45:00 -0800 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="vinyl"><![CDATA[vinyl]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/orlando-record-stores-trip-and-review</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/XWKGl.jpg" alt="image" /></p><p>I was in Orlando, FL for a few days, and was lucky to have a chance to go check out a few stores (thanks for the suggestions!). There&rsquo;s a Henry Rollins quote about how you can&rsquo;t really get a good feel for a town until you visit its record stores, so I always try to check them out whenever I go somewhere. This was by no means an exhaustive trip, but it was still fun and I wanted to share my findings:</p><p>The first stop on the trip was <strong><a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/retro-records-orlando">Retro Records</a></strong>. Maybe it was just that what I&rsquo;m interested in didn&rsquo;t really fit in with what he had, but I wasn&rsquo;t digging this place. Everything is sorted really well, but most used things were either of not great condition, over-priced, or both. Still, he has a <em>lot</em> of stuff, so that was cool. Didn&rsquo;t pick anything up there.</p><p>Next up was <strong><a href="http://www.parkavecds.com/">Park Ave CDs</a></strong>. This place is amazing. They have a huge selection of new stuff, and 2 categories of used records. One section is cleaned and graded. They have little cards on the top of the racks that explain in detail their grading and pricing procedures. Everything was well-priced and explained (many individual records also say why they were graded in a specific way). They also have a lot of CDs if you&rsquo;re looking for those. At the front of the store, they have these 15 record grab bags for $12 (you don&rsquo;t know what is in them). I grabbed one and was pleasantly surprised. Most of the time these grab bags are off-condition, crappy records, but these were pretty much all in very nice condition and not just super common things. My bag was an interesting mix of rock, pop, electronic, jazz, and others. Just really cool to hear some new music (and the Men Without Hats Album was a nice touch, too). The staff here is super helpful and friendly. I asked where the used records were, and rather than just pointing, the guy walked me over to the used section and explained everything to me. I talked to a few other people who worked there and they were really cool, too. The store has a whole box of Third Man Records items and a section of local/Florida bands.   <br /><strong>Picked up:</strong> NOFX &ndash; 22 Songs&hellip;, Jack White &ndash; Love Interruption, Carl Sagan &ndash; A Glorious Dawn, 15 LP Grab Bag</p><p>The last stop was <strong><a href="http://rock-n-rollheaven.com/">Rock and Roll Heaven</a></strong>. This place is <em>huge</em>. Tons of rock, jazz, and a really big rap/hip-hop section. They also have a really large number of 45s. Most things seemed fairly priced. Some stuff was over-priced, but from what it looked like the rare stuff (at least what I knew to be rare) was fairly priced. Another really nice thing is that every genre was sorted by artist. Most stores I&rsquo;ve been to neglect at least one genre (ie. rock will be sorted, but there will just be a &lsquo;jazz&rsquo; section). Here, however, they spent the time to sort every section, and that made it really easy to find stuff.   <br /><strong>Picked up:</strong> The Don Ellis Orchestra &ndash; Live in 3⅔/4 Time</p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I was in Orlando, FL for a few days, and was lucky to have a chance to go check out a few stores (thanks for the suggestions!). There’s a Henry Rollins quote about how you can’t really get a good feel for a town until you visit its record stores, ...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Wed Mar 07 15:45:00 -0800 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Wed Mar 07 15:45:00 -0800 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>108948456</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>orlando-record-stores-trip-and-review</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Record Store Day 2012</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/record-store-day-2012</link>	<pubDate>Sat Apr 21 07:22:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>			<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/record-store-day-2012</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://instagr.am/p/JrtSJCL2Au"></a><img src="http://distilleryimage6.instagram.com/aa1896208bb311e19dc71231380fe523_7.jpg" alt="" /></p><p>So, today was (is) <a href="http://www.recordstoreday.com/Home">Record Store Day</a>. There were some really good releases this year. My day started just before 7am, when I headed out towards <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Double-Decker-Records/125444281003">Double Decker</a> in Allentown.</p><p><a href="http://instagr.am/p/JrcDhBr2Ml/"><img src="http://distilleryimage5.instagram.com/a22f82088b9e11e192e91231381b3d7a_7.jpg" alt="" /></a><br /><em>Getting an early start</em></p><p><a href="http://instagr.am/p/JrfsPAL2NZ/"><img src="http://distilleryimage5.instagram.com/12810cbc8ba311e1af7612313813f8e8_7.jpg" alt="" /></a></p><p>When I got to Double Decker around 7:20, there were some people already in line ahead of me. The kid in front is a senior in high school. He was visiting Muhlenberg for an accepted candidates day, and made his mom leave an hour early from Connecticut to get to Double Decker before his day at college. He had arrived at 5:55am. His mother was asleep in the car.</p><p>Double Decker opened at 8 and we all filed to the RSD section to make our selections. When I was paying, I noticed that their copy of the Teen Idles' <em>Minor Disturbance EP</em> was still there. Almost picked it up, but $550 was a little pricy for me.</p><p>After Double Decker, I headed over to <a href="http://cdcenterpa.com/">Compact Disc Center</a> in Bethlehem. I'd never actually been there, and they really live up to their name - it's mostly CDs. Nevertheless, the Dave Brubeck 10" caught my eye. They said they had had the Gorillaz 10", but had run out. Bummer.</p><p>Here are some pictures of everything I got. The full list is <a href="http://empty-winter-789.heroku.com/?search=RSD+4%2F2012">here</a>. The Flaming Lips album is insane looking and sounds awesome. I'm excited to hear the new material from both The Black Angels and The Hives (that's a throwback group for me). Also, check out my sweet free totebag! I'm still on the hunt for the Frank Turner <em>I Still Believe 7"</em> (which I think may be a UK exclusive) and the Gorillaz 10".</p><p><a href="http://instagr.am/p/JrtSJCL2Au"></a><img src="http://distilleryimage6.instagram.com/aa1896208bb311e19dc71231380fe523_7.jpg" alt="" /></p><p><a href="http://instagr.am/p/JrteIHr2Av/"><img src="http://distilleryimage7.instagram.com/e49ee1828bb311e1af7612313813f8e8_7.jpg" alt="" /></a></p><p><a href="http://instagr.am/p/JryQOJr2Cp/"><img src="http://distilleryimage5.instagram.com/bb383f368bb911e1be6a12313820455d_7.jpg" alt="" /></a></p><p><a href="http://instagr.am/p/Jr5HrTr2GB/"><img src="http://distilleryimage9.instagram.com/1cffbd7c8bc211e1989612313815112c_7.jpg" alt="" /></a></p><p><a href="http://instagr.am/p/Jr5HrTr2GB/"><p>​</p></a></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[So, today was (is) Record Store Day. There were some really good releases this year. My day started just before 7am, when I headed out towards Double Decker in Allentown. Getting an early start When I got to Double Decker around 7:20, there were s...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Sat Apr 21 07:22:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sat Apr 21 07:22:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>124830412</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>record-store-day-2012</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Cataloguais - a simple cataloging app</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/cataloguais-a-simple-cataloging-app</link>	<pubDate>Sun Sep 25 17:44:23 -0700 2011</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="programming"><![CDATA[programming]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/cataloguais-a-simple-cataloging-app</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, as I started collecting vinyls recently, I needed a good way to keep track of them all. Not satisfied with a simple Google Spreadsheet and always looking for interesting programming problems, I decided to roll my own solution. Here were my requirements</p><ul><li><strong>Simple (as always)</strong>: I wanted the collection to be displayed in an easy-to-follow table, and adding/editing items should be a simple process.</li><li><strong>Fluid Schema</strong>: if I want to add/remove attributes, I should be able to do that</li><li><strong>Public</strong>: I want to be able to share this collection without worry or fear of other people messing with it without permission.</li></ul><p>Enter <a href="https://github.com/GordonDiggs/cataloguais" target="_blank">cataloguais</a>. Built on Sinatra, MongoDB and jQuery, cataloguais is basically exactly what I wanted. This is not my first time working with Sinatra or jQuery, but my first foray into MongoDB. MongoDB gets a lot of flak, but I think this is a good use-case for it. Its in-memory, fluid schema architecture lends itself well to my collection of all-string objects. Plus, MongoMapper makes it easy to manipulate and fetch objects, adding a lot of methods I'm used to using with Rails.</p><p>It was an interesting task writing something that I'm going to use specifically to be designed for more general use cases. I wanted to write code that anyone could use to keep track of their collection. Thus, the schema is specified in a settings.yml file and applied each time the app spins up.</p><p>To be honest, I'm not exactly happy with the authentication as it stands. It's a plain-text string comparison. I'm thinking of moving over to an Oauth setup/administration, which could be cool. The lock works on a really simple level as-is for now.</p><p>All in all, cataloguais has managed to fullfill my needs really well. Check out the code on <a href="https://github.com/GordonDiggs/cataloguais">github</a>&nbsp;and see it in action <a href="http://vinyl.gordondiggs.com">here</a>.</p><p><em>A cause de ma nouvelle collection des disques, j'avais besoin d'un bon fa&ccedil;on &agrave; les cataloguer. Je n'&eacute;tais pas satisfait de Google Spreadsheet et parce que je toujours cherches des probl&egrave;mes interessantes de la programmation, j'ai decid&eacute; &agrave; faire une solution moi-m&ecirc;me. Mes besoins &eacute;taient:</em></p><ul><li><em><strong>Simple (comme toujours)</strong>: Je voulais que la collection serait montr&eacute;e dans une table simple, et ajouter/supprimer des chose doivent &ecirc;tre facile.</em></li><li><em><strong>Sch&eacute;ma liquide</strong>: Si on veut ajouter/supprimer des attributs, on doit pouvoir le faire.</em></li><li><em><strong>Public:</strong>&nbsp;Je veut montret ma collection sans peur que des gens traficoteraient.</em></li></ul><p><em>Voila <a href="https://github.com/GordonDiggs/cataloguais">cataloguais</a>. Utilisant Sinatra, MongoDB et jQuery, cataloguais est exactement dont j'avais besoin. Ce n'est pas ma premi&eacute;re exp&eacute;rience avec Sinatra ou jQuery, mais c'est ma premi&eacute;re avec MongoDB. MongoDB re&ccedil;oit beaucoup de critiques, mais je pense que ce soit un bon emploi de lui. Son in-memory, sch&eacute;ma liquide architecture se conf&egrave;re &agrave; ma collection des strings. Plus, MongoMapper la rend facile &agrave; changer des objets, avec beaucoup de m&eacute;thodes avec qui je suis familier &agrave; cause de Rails.</em></p><p><em>C'&eacute;tait interessant &agrave; ecrire quelque chose pour moi-m&ecirc;me qui doit &ecirc;tre g&eacute;n&eacute;ral aussi. J'ai voulu &eacute;crire du code pour permettre n'importe qui &agrave; cataloguer leur collection. Donc, le sch&eacute;ma est sp&eacute;cifi&eacute; dans un fichier settings.yml et appliqu&eacute; chaque fois l'application commence.</em></p><p><em>Etre franc, je ne suis pas content avec l'authentication comme elle est maintenant. C'est une comparasion du texte. Je pense d'utiliser Oauth. Mais l'authentication marche pour maintenant.</em></p><p><em>Cataloguais me suffit exactement. Voila le code sur <a href="https://github.com/GordonDiggs/cataloguais">github</a> et le produi <a href="http://vinyl.gordondiggs.com">ici</a>.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[So, as I started collecting vinyls recently, I needed a good way to keep track of them all. Not satisfied with a simple Google Spreadsheet and always looking for interesting programming problems, I decided to roll my own solution. Here were my req...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Sun Sep 25 17:44:23 -0700 2011</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sun Sep 25 17:44:23 -0700 2011</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>71706607</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>cataloguais-a-simple-cataloging-app</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 7: I'm near a boat!</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-7-im-near-a-boat</link>	<pubDate>Thu May 31 15:35:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-7-im-near-a-boat</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today was an especially packed day, filled with a lot of walking. You see, east of Vieux Nice is the port area, which I previously had no real reason to visit (also, it's a far walk, and I like walking). However, I read about the Mus&eacute;e de Terra Amata, which was supposed to be pretty cool, and it's over there, so I decided to go check it out.</p><p>But before the museum was the Italian Festival. Right across the street from my hotel, this festival has started. Vendors from Italy bring cheese, meat, bread, oil, wine, etc. from Italy and present it here. I think it's the first time that they've had it, and it's pretty cool. There are a lot of free samples, and I managed to basically eat a meal for free just wandering around. Notable sights include huge blocks of cheese that I thought were bread until I smelled them, giant blocks of prosciutto, and whole truffles (which I had never seen before). Entrance is free, too! There are two places offering porchetta, which I've wanted to try for a long time, so lunch tomorrow will be there for sure (I wasn't hungry after all the sampling today).</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/okTjy.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2vQqX.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Cheese, disguised as bread</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/nq7My.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Actual bread</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2oHRT.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/u05GE.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Truffles. Mmm.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/QUezX.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Do you think they'd let me take this on the plane as my "personal item"?</p><p>After checking out the festival, I headed over to the museum. The walk was long, but along the beach so it was nice (it also wasn't too hot today). Along the way, I found this human sundial. You stand on the marker and it will tell you what time it is! It's pre-DST, though, so it was an hour off.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/MuTaU.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>The Terra Amata museum itself is small (noticing a theme here?), but was still pretty cool. The main attraction is this giant fossil platform they dug up on the beach, with lots of fossils in it, including the oldest know human foot print! Upstairs were other local fossils of humans and animals, as well as ancient tools. It presents an ancient history of the Nice area, and how they used the beach, the animals, and the environment. They also have a recreation of a hut that was on the beach and that was used as living quarters.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/OXmCM.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/FbjwH.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/h2qfL.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After the museum, I wandered a bit around the harbor area. There's not a lot around there (a bunch of restaurants along the water, though), but there is a theater if you want to find out when to see plays, and an area full of antique stores. Most of the stores are high-end antiques: tables, paintings, large elephant sculptures, things of that sort. If you're interested more in trinkets (aka me), the place to go is Les Puces de Nice. It's a small antique market that's similar to the one at Cours Selaya, but much much smaller. Still, there are a fair number of vendors there and some cool stuff. The layout and the enclosed nature of the market reminded me of the market in NYC near Astor Place that was tented in on a lot off the street (I'm not sure if it exists anymore), but of much higher quality. Definitely check this market out.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/UsLom.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2DA92.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After some more wandering and scenery gazing (because it's important to appreciate the beauty of where you are), I headed back to my hotel to relax and soak my feet. For dinner, I was in the mood for seafood, so I headed back towards the harbor and came across Le Lunel, a restaurant right on the harbor. I started with the fish soup, which was basically like bouillabaisse lite, and very tasty. Next I had black pollock, which I had never had or heard of as far as I know. It was also very good. I finished with tiramisu, which was really quite good; it had a nice coffee flavor and wasn't too mushy (the layers were distinct). I also had beer instead of wine because I haven't had much beer while I was here, and the wine choices didn't really interest me.</p><p><em>First Course: Soupe de poisson</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/UzTkz.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Second Course: Filet de lieu au safran</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/RHlrv.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Dessert: Tiramisu</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/O7I9Q.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After dinner, I stopped by the Arts and Crafts market at Cours Selaya, which just started tonight. This market runs every night (6pm to midnight) except Mondays until September. I had heard it didn't start until tomorrow, but as I was walking along the promenade, some shiny jewelry caught my eye and I went to inspect. Cours Selaya at night is usually dedicated to the restaurants, they add tables to the middle where the day's market normally is, so the crafts market finds itself filling in the gaps, which adds an interesting dynamic. It took a lot of energy not to stand next to someone's dinner table, inspecting as if I was still looking at a table of wares. The stands are, for the most part, local residents selling their creations. There is a lot of jewelry, but also other handmade items, like bags, paintings, wooden puzzles and games, stauettes, and even beautiful handmade marble moartar and pestles. I always like supporting local artists whenever I can, as well as asking whoever made an item for details about it, so it was fun to browse and inspect.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ThsfG.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>I headed back to my hotel, happy of my walk back, and it wasn't long until I started hearing loud explosions. There was a fireworks show originating out in the sea. I'm not sure what the occasion was, but it was certainly fun to watch the end of.</p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Today was an especially packed day, filled with a lot of walking. You see, east of Vieux Nice is the port area, which I previously had no real reason to visit (also, it's a far walk, and I like walking). However, I read about the Musée de Terra Am...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Thu May 31 15:35:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Thu May 31 15:35:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>134997614</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-7-im-near-a-boat</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 4: I think it's a holiday?</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-4-i-think-its-a-holiday</link>	<pubDate>Mon May 28 15:47:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-4-i-think-its-a-holiday</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mondays are kind of weird days. A lot of things are closed anyway, and it didn't help that today was the first time in a few years that France has recognized the day after Pentecost as a holiday. From what I can gather, schools were closed, but businesses remained open (unless they close on Mondays anyway). I was really glad that the antiques market at Cours Selaya, where the spice market normally is, was open today. Here's a tip for Nice: if you stay near Cours Selaya, check it out every day (and, if you can, morning as well as night), since there are a number of different markets there at different hours. Anyway, my day began a little late. I clearly didn't think about how much of an endurance test this trip would be, so in a way I'm glad that everything was closed today since I was forced to just relax for a while (something I don't usually think of doing when I travel).&nbsp;</p><p>So, I headed out late towards the antique market. I was not ready for just how big this thing is. It's awesome. There's a big variety of things there, from old prints to figurines to cookware to furniture and trinkets, and lots of silverware. Oh yeah, and records. I didn't find anything good (a lot of Johnny Hallyday, who I would describe as the French Elvis, but a british woman nearby me described as a French Donny Osmond. To each their own), but it was fun to flip through all the stuff. I also saw this beautiful set of copper pots that I would have bought if I thought there was any way of getting them back to the States.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/WXHDi.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/9ME12.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/mnpzL.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/yrWcR.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/qBnA9.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/MCGQn.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>For lunch, I knew that I wanted to try Socca, a ni&ccedil;oise specialty. Socca is a pancake made of chickpea flour. It's made in a dish similar to a deep dish pizza dish, and is baked in a pizza oven usually. It is tasty, very very tasty:</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ZqzsA.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>I also had some gelato, also common to this area and part of the heavy Italian influence in Nice (see also: fresh pasta and gnocchi, as well as pizza). After that, I took the opportunity to do some gift shopping, since the stores were really the only things open today. I also spent a while browsing at Fnac, which is fun. The Fnac in Nice has a big record section, so that was fun to look through (also useful, they separate French artists from non-French artists). I was fondly reminded of hanging out in HMV and Tower Records with friends when I was younger, picking up random CDs and scanning them to hear them. I also used the European keyboard layout for the first time in a while, which is very similar to the QWERTY layout, but different enough to throw you off. Also, the period symbol requires pressing shift - what's that all about?</p><p>After some more browsing at stores (I was tempted by the clothes at Celio), I decided that it was time to just relax, so I spent some time on the beach working on my tan lines and reading. Then, I took a nap and woke up to go find dinner. I found C&ocirc;t&eacute; Marais, and it was insanely good. The staff was really friendly, and the menu was small (which is a good sign in restaurants here, it means it changes often). The waiter asked where I was from, and often asked for the English equivalents of things while he took me through the menu, item by item, describing what each dish was and how it was made. He was very tolerant of my sheer lack of understanding of wines, and knew exactly what I wanted when I told him that I enjoyed the other local wines I'd been drinking. This is very much a restaurant for locals; everyone knew everyone by name, and there was a great energy about the place. As I left after the meal, the staff shook my hand and everyone, including all the patrons, said good night. I've never understood the stereotype that the French are unwelcoming, since experiences like tonight have, more often than not, been the norm for me. It was also really nice tonight, so I sat outside to eat.</p><p><em>First Course: Petit Saint-Marcellin r&ocirc;ti (my new favorite cheese)</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/w7ETH.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Second Course: Foie de Veau d&eacute;glac&eacute; au Cassis</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/goJdj.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Dessert: Fondant au chocolat noir</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/5vP0Z.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Mondays are kind of weird days. A lot of things are closed anyway, and it didn't help that today was the first time in a few years that France has recognized the day after Pentecost as a holiday. From what I can gather, schools were closed, but bu...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Mon May 28 15:47:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Mon May 28 15:47:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>134240117</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-4-i-think-its-a-holiday</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>			<wp:comment>			<wp:comment_id>11072346</wp:comment_id>							<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Silagh White]]></wp:comment_author>				<wp:comment_author_url><![CDATA[http://silagh.blogspot.com/]]></wp:comment_author_url>						<wp:comment_date>Tue May 29 09:42:04 -0700 2012</wp:comment_date>			<wp:comment_date_gmt>Tue May 29 09:42:04 -0700 2012</wp:comment_date_gmt>			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[ooh, travel with food porn. This post is making me drool! - and it reminded me to put the gelato maker in the freezer!]]></wp:comment_content>			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>		</wp:comment>	</item><item>	<title>Recipe: Slow Cooker Chili</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/recipe-slow-cooker-chili</link>	<pubDate>Sun Oct 02 17:24:00 -0700 2011</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="cooking"><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/recipe-slow-cooker-chili</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In my house, there are 5 of us &ndash; we each take turn cooking one night per week. A few weeks ago, I decided to make chili. My housemates and I are all about the heat, so I really wanted to make something with some kick. The following is based very heavily on <a href="http://www.tasteofhome.com/Recipes/Spicy-Slow-Cooked-Chili">this recipe</a>. I didn&rsquo;t manage to catch a photo of it, but it was super tasty and pretty hot (though not unmanageably so). Enjoy!</p><h2>Ingredients</h2><ul><li>2 pounds ground beef</li><li>3 (mostly) seeded habaneros</li><li>3 cans (16 ounces each) kidney beans, rinsed and drained</li><li>1 can (6 ounces) tomato paste</li><li>1 medium onion, chopped</li><li>1 poblano pepper, seeded and diced</li><li>2 teaspoons chili powder</li><li>2 teaspoons cider vinegar</li><li>1 teaspoon garlic powder</li><li>1 teaspoon dried oregano</li><li>&frac12; teaspoon ground cinnamon</li><li>&frac14; teaspoon pepper</li><li>3 cups tomato juice</li></ul><h2>Directions</h2><ol><li>Brown beef in a large skillet and drain. Transfer meat to slow cooker.</li><li>Add all other ingredients and mix.</li><li>Set the slow cooker to low. Cook for 5 hours.</li></ol><h2>Notes</h2><p>As you can see, this is a super easy chili to make. You can adjust the heat to your liking. And as always, be careful when handling those habaneros &ndash; capsaicin will hurt you.</p><hr /><p>Chez moi, il y a 5 gens. Nous cuisinons à tour de rôle un jour par semaine. Il y a des semaines, j'ai décidé à faire du chili. Mes amis et moi aiment le goût épicé, et j'ai vraiment voulu faire quelque chose avec un &ldquo;recul.&rdquo; Ce qui suit est fondé sur <a href="http://www.tasteofhome.com/Recipes/Spicy-Slow-Cooked-Chili">cette recette</a>. Je n'ai pas pris un photo du chili, mais c'était delicieux et très épicé (mais pas trop).</p><h2>Ingrédients</h2><ul><li>2 livres de boeuf</li><li>3 habaneros, épépinés</li><li>3 16oz boites des haricots rouge</li><li>1 6oz boite de la pâte des tomates</li><li>1 oignon moyen, émincé</li><li>1 poplano, épépiné et coupé</li><li>2 cuillères à thé de la poudre de chili</li><li>2 cuillères à thé du vinaigre de cidre</li><li>1 cuillère à thé de l'ail en poudre</li><li>1 cuillère à thé de l'origan sec</li><li>&frac12; cuillère à thé de la cannelle en poudre</li><li>&frac14; cuillère à thé du poivre</li><li>3 tasses du jus du tomate</li></ul><h2>Instructions</h2><ol><li>Faites dorer la boeuf et la faites dégorger. Mettez la boeuf dans une cocotte.</li><li>Ajoutez les autres ingrédients et les mélangez.</li><li>Cuisinez à feu doux pour 5 heures.</li></ol><h2>Notes</h2><p>Ce chili est super facile à préparer. On peut changer les piments à la choix. Comme toujours, faites attention avec les habaneros &ndash; le capsaicin est dangereux.</p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In my house, there are 5 of us – we each take turn cooking one night per week. A few weeks ago, I decided to make chili. My housemates and I are all about the heat, so I really wanted to make something with some kick. The following is based very...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Sun Oct 02 17:24:00 -0700 2011</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sun Oct 02 17:24:00 -0700 2011</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>73660947</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>recipe-slow-cooker-chili</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>On Meditation and Learning</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/on-meditation-and-learning</link>	<pubDate>Wed Dec 05 06:31:00 -0800 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>			<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/on-meditation-and-learning</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Back in September, I attended Rocky Mountain Ruby in Boulder, CO. At the beginning of each day, <a href="https://twitter.com/mikegehard" target="_blank">Mike Gehard</a>&nbsp;led the entire group in a quick meditation. He raised a point about context switching in the work day, and about using meditation to regain focus and be more productive. I used to meditate a lot when I practiced yoga, and had not in a long time until September. Recently, as I and the Paperless Post team head into our busiest time of year, I found myself context switching much more often at work. For me, that is not a challenge. I enjoy jumping around to use my brain on many different things throughout the day, getting my hands dirty and juggling. What I find challenging is calming that excitement and energy at the end of the day. As I came home every day, still switching, and seeking something to restore some quiet, I came back to meditation. For just 5 minutes a day, right when I get home, I sit on my hard wood floor, and let the thoughts drift away from my mind. Yogic philosophy says that "the Self exists in the space between thoughts." I don't really care much about that, particularly because I like thinking as much as I do, but there is something to be said for the feeling of <em>not thinking</em>&nbsp;for a period of time. To just sit in quiet and in peace, for the longest 5 minutes of the day, relieves the need to jump around. So, in the end, like Mike said, meditation restores focus and eases the context switching.</p><p>Meditation is inherently not about thinking. Therefore, I view the opposite of mediation to be reflection: active thinking after some experience. Through reflection, we often find the lessons or the mere purposes for an experience. If it's an experience we repeat, then by reflecting upon it, we find its true value. I think this is an incredibly important act as well. I reflect mainly on what I learn every day, because learning is important. Immediately after graduating, I realized that no one would be forcing me to learn anymore. No one would impose a deadline for me to be required to spit back information and prove that I have learned hard facts or processes. For a short while, this was incredibly liberating. I had the freedom to not learn anything actively. I could let experiences come and go and just pick up whatever it was that I learned along the way. After a time, though, my desire and need to learn returned. Luckily, I am in a job where I learn every day. Some days, I learn more about how a certain piece of application code works, or how we use a specific technology. These acquisitions of knowledge, though beneficial, are not as useful as a more active search. Real learning takes digging and playing. So, every day, I try to dig and play as much as I can. Most days, I succeed. I learn about a language or a technology. I learn about grinds of coffee. I learn about food and beer. I learn about current events. And, most importantly, I reflect on the day, to fully find what I learned that day.&nbsp;</p><p>It is the pairing of meditation, not thinking, and reflection, thinking, that truly pulls a day together. It doesn't take long, no more than 10 minutes, but it makes everything much clearer.</p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Back in September, I attended Rocky Mountain Ruby in Boulder, CO. At the beginning of each day, Mike Gehard led the entire group in a quick meditation. He raised a point about context switching in the work day, and about using meditation to regain...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Wed Dec 05 06:31:00 -0800 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Wed Dec 05 06:31:00 -0800 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>170893289</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>on-meditation-and-learning</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Welcome!</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/welcome</link>	<pubDate>Thu Sep 22 08:58:00 -0700 2011</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="general"><![CDATA[general]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/welcome</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, I guess this is my new attempt at having a blog? Seems like a good thing to do. So, what am I going to post about? I have a few topics in mind: collecting vinyl, cooking, the drinking and brewing of beer, programming, and my life as a college senior. So, I hope you stick around or subscribe! More soon.</p><p><em>Je suppose que c'est ma nouvelle tentative d'avoir un blog. Il me semble que c'est une bonne chose</em><span style="font-family: Charis SIL, Junicode, Palemonas MUFI, Gentium, Cambria, Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: 15px;">&nbsp;&agrave;</span></span><em>&nbsp;faire. Donc, de quoi est-ce que je vais &eacute;crire? Je peux penser des quelques sujets: ma collection des disques, cuisinant, le buvant et la brassage de la bi&egrave;re, la programmation, et ma vie comme un&nbsp;</em><em>&eacute;tudiant. J'esp</em><em>&egrave;re que vous restez-ici ou vous vous s'abonnez! Plus arrive.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[So, I guess this is my new attempt at having a blog? Seems like a good thing to do. So, what am I going to post about? I have a few topics in mind: collecting vinyl, cooking, the drinking and brewing of beer, programming, and my life as a college ...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Thu Sep 22 08:58:00 -0700 2011</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Thu Sep 22 08:58:00 -0700 2011</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>71700707</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>welcome</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>Nice Trip - Day 5: Record Stores and more</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-5-record-stores-and-more</link>	<pubDate>Tue May 29 15:41:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>				<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>			<category domain="tag" nicename="vinyl"><![CDATA[vinyl]]></category>		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-5-record-stores-and-more</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have to begin this post with some apologies. Apologies first to the record collectors who just want to read about the record stores and apologies to non-collectors who may not be interested in such detailed accounts of record stores in Nice. I trust that you will skim through the parts that are less interesting to you.</p><p>There's a quote, I believe by Henry Rollins in <em>Black Coffee Blues,</em>&nbsp;about how he didn't really start to understand the cities he visited until he began going to their record stores, seeing the music bought and sold, and talking to owners of shops. I would also add that venturing out to visit stores will take you through parts of a town you may not otherwise get to see, particularly if it is far from where you are or if there are no other attractions in the area. I found some stores by searching "disquaire" on Google Maps in Nice, and did a little bit of Traveling Salesman Problem solving to devise a walking tour of the record stores I had found. There are one or two that I have found separate from this list, so I will add info if I get a chance to visit them over the next few days.</p><p>I began by heading northwest of my hotel, into what appears to be a big shopping district in Nice. I had no idea this was there, so I will definitely be exploring that direction a bit more thoroughly (I didn't want to get off track of my directions). I seem to have gotten some misinformation from Google, since what was supposed to be my first destination was a salon, and did not sell records. Regardless, the walk was still fun and worth it, so I wasn't too disheartened. My next stop was Fnac. For those who don't know, Fnac is a chain of stores that sells anything related to culture, so music, movies, computers, books, TVs, food, clothing, etc. They pretty much sell everything and anything. In this trip, I have visited the Fnacs in both Nice and Cannes, as well as the Virgin store in Nice (I'm lumping them all together since I distinguish them from independent stores). Of the three, Fnac in Nice definitely has the best vinyl selection. There is a dedicated section to vinyl, and they even distinguish between French artists and non-French artists, which was great for me because I was only interested in the French stuff. Also important to note is that Fnac only sells new records - you won't find any used items there. I picked up these two Dionysos singles:</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/fNsmO.jpg?1" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>The next stop was Hit Import. They had a somewhat small vinyl selection (though for electronic stuff, they seemed to have a lot), and there were a lot of imports, as the name implies. I didn't buy anything, but it was a cool store with lots of CDs and a good variety of genres. They also seemed to have a focus on metal, with more genre specifications for different kinds of metal than any other genre, so if you are looking for that, definitely go check them out. Sadly, they didn't have a listening station, so I didn't buy the record I was on the fence about.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/AbYv1.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/CTKqk.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>The next stop was Sonic Import, which is literally around the corner from Hit Import. They are a very small store, with only one wall of vinyl, but the stuff there is incredibly well-sorted by genre. They have a selection of both new and used, and again a fair amount of imports, but a greater selection of French records than Hit Import (at least right now). Sadly, no listening station again, but I had a good feeling about this Jean-Pierre Mas record, so I bought it.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2ocj2.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/J5RyW.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>The last stop was Crazy Rhythm. This store certainly was crazy. The place is jam-packed with records and books. I had to take my backpack off just to fit in the aisles. They have a really big jazz selection, and a lot of imports as well. I spent a long time digging in this store, and I'm pretty sure the owner was changing the music he was playing based on which section I was in. It was pretty funny. I managed to find a French punk rock 7", which I'm really excited about, as well as this Disney read-along record and an older French record as well. If you want to lose a lot of time, definitely check this place out.</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/wXm3e.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>Prices seemed fair at all the places I visited, and I would recommend checking all of them out when you are in town.</p><p>After the record store voyage, I decided it was time to go relax and read on the beach, so I put on my bathing suit, grabbed my towel (always have your towel) and headed down to the beach. I actually went in the water briefly. The Mediterranean isn't warm like the Agean or the Pacific, but it nearly isn't as cold as the Atlantic, and it was refreshing. I think my back may be sunburned a bit, but I think it will be ok. I don't know if it shows in the pictures, but you can <em>very</em>&nbsp;faintly make out the coast of Corsica across the sea from the beach. Amazing how far you can see. It's also fun to watch planes come in and out of the Nice airport, which is very close all things considered. The beaches here aren't sandy - they're rocky, which is great for me because sand is what I hate about beaches. Funnily enough, many of the beach spots have added these patches of sand, almost like sand boxes to their portion of the beach. Also, the rocks are somewhat uncomfortable to walk on, but are all very smooth.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2k5gy.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/tx26f.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p>After some more time relaxing and re-reading the second book in the Ender's Game series, I headed out for dinner. For a few days now, I have been wanting to go to Lou Pistou, which is supposedly the best place to have tripes &agrave; la ni&ccedil;oise, a local specialty. For those who don't know, tripe is intenstine (in this case of a cow). I have eaten my fair share of stranger foods, from guinea pig in Ecuador, to aligator in Florida, to Boudin Noir (blood sausage) in Paris, but I have never had tripe. Here in Nice, they either serve tripe in this dish, or as a sausage called andouillette. Both dishes are somewhat smelly, though both delicious (a couple next to me at C&ocirc;t&eacute; Marais sampled the andouillete last night). Lou Pistou serves their tripe with chickpea fries, which are incredibly tasty, and also do a much better job of absorbing sauce than normal potato fries. The restaurant itself was very nice; small and cozy, with a real family feeling to it. It was also cool because you could see into the kitchen, and watch the chef prepare your food. As I ordered, I was informed that one of the dessert options was profiteroles, but that it has to be ordered at the beginning of the meal, since it is prepared <em>au moment</em>. I believe it was the chocolate sauce that was prepared specifically, though I didn't ask. I jumped on the opportunity, not just as a lover of profiteroles, but also because I've always thought there was something cool about desserts that take a while to make.</p><p><em>First Course: P&acirc;tes fra&icirc;ches vertes au pistou</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ZW7qQ.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Second Course: Tripes &agrave; la ni&ccedil;oise</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/3Lf3v.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p><p><em>Dessert: Profiteroles</em></p><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/8Gqtt.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I have to begin this post with some apologies. Apologies first to the record collectors who just want to read about the record stores and apologies to non-collectors who may not be interested in such detailed accounts of record stores in Nice. I t...]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Tue May 29 15:41:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Tue May 29 15:41:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>134481859</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-5-record-stores-and-more</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item><item>	<title>My Lightning talk on Ruby and SQL from Rocky Mountain Ruby '12</title>	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/my-lightning-talk-on-ruby-and-sql-from-rocky</link>	<pubDate>Thu Nov 01 07:13:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>			<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/my-lightning-talk-on-ruby-and-sql-from-rocky</guid>	<description></description>	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In September, I attended Rocky Mountain Ruby in Boulder, CO. I jumped up on stage for a few minutes to give this lightning talk:</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/1g-VbdDRtXs" frameborder="0" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>]]></content:encoded>	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In September, I attended Rocky Mountain Ruby in Boulder, CO. I jumped up on stage for a few minutes to give this lightning talk:]]></excerpt:encoded>		<wp:post_date>Thu Nov 01 07:13:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>	<wp:post_date_gmt>Thu Nov 01 07:13:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>	<wp:post_id>167264601</wp:post_id>	<wp:post_name>my-lightning-talk-on-ruby-and-sql-from-rocky</wp:post_name>	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>	</item></channel></rss>