<item>
	<title>Nice Trip - Day 4: I think it's a holiday?</title>
	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-4-i-think-its-a-holiday</link>
	<pubDate>Mon May 28 15:47:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-4-i-think-its-a-holiday</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mondays are kind of weird days. A lot of things are closed anyway, and it didn't help that today was the first time in a few years that France has recognized the day after Pentecost as a holiday. From what I can gather, schools were closed, but businesses remained open (unless they close on Mondays anyway). I was really glad that the antiques market at Cours Selaya, where the spice market normally is, was open today. Here's a tip for Nice: if you stay near Cours Selaya, check it out every day (and, if you can, morning as well as night), since there are a number of different markets there at different hours. Anyway, my day began a little late. I clearly didn't think about how much of an endurance test this trip would be, so in a way I'm glad that everything was closed today since I was forced to just relax for a while (something I don't usually think of doing when I travel).&nbsp;</p>
<p>So, I headed out late towards the antique market. I was not ready for just how big this thing is. It's awesome. There's a big variety of things there, from old prints to figurines to cookware to furniture and trinkets, and lots of silverware. Oh yeah, and records. I didn't find anything good (a lot of Johnny Hallyday, who I would describe as the French Elvis, but a british woman nearby me described as a French Donny Osmond. To each their own), but it was fun to flip through all the stuff. I also saw this beautiful set of copper pots that I would have bought if I thought there was any way of getting them back to the States.&nbsp;</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/WXHDi.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/9ME12.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/mnpzL.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/yrWcR.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/qBnA9.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/MCGQn.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>For lunch, I knew that I wanted to try Socca, a ni&ccedil;oise specialty. Socca is a pancake made of chickpea flour. It's made in a dish similar to a deep dish pizza dish, and is baked in a pizza oven usually. It is tasty, very very tasty:</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ZqzsA.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>I also had some gelato, also common to this area and part of the heavy Italian influence in Nice (see also: fresh pasta and gnocchi, as well as pizza). After that, I took the opportunity to do some gift shopping, since the stores were really the only things open today. I also spent a while browsing at Fnac, which is fun. The Fnac in Nice has a big record section, so that was fun to look through (also useful, they separate French artists from non-French artists). I was fondly reminded of hanging out in HMV and Tower Records with friends when I was younger, picking up random CDs and scanning them to hear them. I also used the European keyboard layout for the first time in a while, which is very similar to the QWERTY layout, but different enough to throw you off. Also, the period symbol requires pressing shift - what's that all about?</p>
<p>After some more browsing at stores (I was tempted by the clothes at Celio), I decided that it was time to just relax, so I spent some time on the beach working on my tan lines and reading. Then, I took a nap and woke up to go find dinner. I found C&ocirc;t&eacute; Marais, and it was insanely good. The staff was really friendly, and the menu was small (which is a good sign in restaurants here, it means it changes often). The waiter asked where I was from, and often asked for the English equivalents of things while he took me through the menu, item by item, describing what each dish was and how it was made. He was very tolerant of my sheer lack of understanding of wines, and knew exactly what I wanted when I told him that I enjoyed the other local wines I'd been drinking. This is very much a restaurant for locals; everyone knew everyone by name, and there was a great energy about the place. As I left after the meal, the staff shook my hand and everyone, including all the patrons, said good night. I've never understood the stereotype that the French are unwelcoming, since experiences like tonight have, more often than not, been the norm for me. It was also really nice tonight, so I sat outside to eat.</p>
<p><em>First Course: Petit Saint-Marcellin r&ocirc;ti (my new favorite cheese)</em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/w7ETH.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><em>Second Course: Foie de Veau d&eacute;glac&eacute; au Cassis</em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/goJdj.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><em>Dessert: Fondant au chocolat noir</em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/5vP0Z.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Mondays are kind of weird days. A lot of things are closed anyway, and it didn't help that today was the first time in a few years that France has recognized the day after Pentecost as a holiday. From what I can gather, schools were closed, but bu...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Mon May 28 15:47:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Mon May 28 15:47:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>134240117</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-4-i-think-its-a-holiday</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>11072346</wp:comment_id>
			
				<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Silagh White]]></wp:comment_author>
				<wp:comment_author_url><![CDATA[http://silagh.blogspot.com/]]></wp:comment_author_url>
			
			<wp:comment_date>Tue May 29 09:42:04 -0700 2012</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>Tue May 29 09:42:04 -0700 2012</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[ooh, travel with food porn. This post is making me drool! - and it reminded me to put the gelato maker in the freezer!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
		</wp:comment>
	
</item>
