<item>
	<title>Nice Trip - Day 5: Record Stores and more</title>
	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-5-record-stores-and-more</link>
	<pubDate>Tue May 29 15:41:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="vinyl"><![CDATA[vinyl]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-5-record-stores-and-more</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have to begin this post with some apologies. Apologies first to the record collectors who just want to read about the record stores and apologies to non-collectors who may not be interested in such detailed accounts of record stores in Nice. I trust that you will skim through the parts that are less interesting to you.</p>
<p>There's a quote, I believe by Henry Rollins in <em>Black Coffee Blues,</em>&nbsp;about how he didn't really start to understand the cities he visited until he began going to their record stores, seeing the music bought and sold, and talking to owners of shops. I would also add that venturing out to visit stores will take you through parts of a town you may not otherwise get to see, particularly if it is far from where you are or if there are no other attractions in the area. I found some stores by searching "disquaire" on Google Maps in Nice, and did a little bit of Traveling Salesman Problem solving to devise a walking tour of the record stores I had found. There are one or two that I have found separate from this list, so I will add info if I get a chance to visit them over the next few days.</p>
<p>I began by heading northwest of my hotel, into what appears to be a big shopping district in Nice. I had no idea this was there, so I will definitely be exploring that direction a bit more thoroughly (I didn't want to get off track of my directions). I seem to have gotten some misinformation from Google, since what was supposed to be my first destination was a salon, and did not sell records. Regardless, the walk was still fun and worth it, so I wasn't too disheartened. My next stop was Fnac. For those who don't know, Fnac is a chain of stores that sells anything related to culture, so music, movies, computers, books, TVs, food, clothing, etc. They pretty much sell everything and anything. In this trip, I have visited the Fnacs in both Nice and Cannes, as well as the Virgin store in Nice (I'm lumping them all together since I distinguish them from independent stores). Of the three, Fnac in Nice definitely has the best vinyl selection. There is a dedicated section to vinyl, and they even distinguish between French artists and non-French artists, which was great for me because I was only interested in the French stuff. Also important to note is that Fnac only sells new records - you won't find any used items there. I picked up these two Dionysos singles:</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/fNsmO.jpg?1" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>The next stop was Hit Import. They had a somewhat small vinyl selection (though for electronic stuff, they seemed to have a lot), and there were a lot of imports, as the name implies. I didn't buy anything, but it was a cool store with lots of CDs and a good variety of genres. They also seemed to have a focus on metal, with more genre specifications for different kinds of metal than any other genre, so if you are looking for that, definitely go check them out. Sadly, they didn't have a listening station, so I didn't buy the record I was on the fence about.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/AbYv1.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/CTKqk.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>The next stop was Sonic Import, which is literally around the corner from Hit Import. They are a very small store, with only one wall of vinyl, but the stuff there is incredibly well-sorted by genre. They have a selection of both new and used, and again a fair amount of imports, but a greater selection of French records than Hit Import (at least right now). Sadly, no listening station again, but I had a good feeling about this Jean-Pierre Mas record, so I bought it.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2ocj2.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/J5RyW.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>The last stop was Crazy Rhythm. This store certainly was crazy. The place is jam-packed with records and books. I had to take my backpack off just to fit in the aisles. They have a really big jazz selection, and a lot of imports as well. I spent a long time digging in this store, and I'm pretty sure the owner was changing the music he was playing based on which section I was in. It was pretty funny. I managed to find a French punk rock 7", which I'm really excited about, as well as this Disney read-along record and an older French record as well. If you want to lose a lot of time, definitely check this place out.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/wXm3e.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>Prices seemed fair at all the places I visited, and I would recommend checking all of them out when you are in town.</p>
<p>After the record store voyage, I decided it was time to go relax and read on the beach, so I put on my bathing suit, grabbed my towel (always have your towel) and headed down to the beach. I actually went in the water briefly. The Mediterranean isn't warm like the Agean or the Pacific, but it nearly isn't as cold as the Atlantic, and it was refreshing. I think my back may be sunburned a bit, but I think it will be ok. I don't know if it shows in the pictures, but you can <em>very</em>&nbsp;faintly make out the coast of Corsica across the sea from the beach. Amazing how far you can see. It's also fun to watch planes come in and out of the Nice airport, which is very close all things considered. The beaches here aren't sandy - they're rocky, which is great for me because sand is what I hate about beaches. Funnily enough, many of the beach spots have added these patches of sand, almost like sand boxes to their portion of the beach. Also, the rocks are somewhat uncomfortable to walk on, but are all very smooth.&nbsp;</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2k5gy.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/tx26f.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>After some more time relaxing and re-reading the second book in the Ender's Game series, I headed out for dinner. For a few days now, I have been wanting to go to Lou Pistou, which is supposedly the best place to have tripes &agrave; la ni&ccedil;oise, a local specialty. For those who don't know, tripe is intenstine (in this case of a cow). I have eaten my fair share of stranger foods, from guinea pig in Ecuador, to aligator in Florida, to Boudin Noir (blood sausage) in Paris, but I have never had tripe. Here in Nice, they either serve tripe in this dish, or as a sausage called andouillette. Both dishes are somewhat smelly, though both delicious (a couple next to me at C&ocirc;t&eacute; Marais sampled the andouillete last night). Lou Pistou serves their tripe with chickpea fries, which are incredibly tasty, and also do a much better job of absorbing sauce than normal potato fries. The restaurant itself was very nice; small and cozy, with a real family feeling to it. It was also cool because you could see into the kitchen, and watch the chef prepare your food. As I ordered, I was informed that one of the dessert options was profiteroles, but that it has to be ordered at the beginning of the meal, since it is prepared <em>au moment</em>. I believe it was the chocolate sauce that was prepared specifically, though I didn't ask. I jumped on the opportunity, not just as a lover of profiteroles, but also because I've always thought there was something cool about desserts that take a while to make.</p>
<p><em>First Course: P&acirc;tes fra&icirc;ches vertes au pistou</em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ZW7qQ.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><em>Second Course: Tripes &agrave; la ni&ccedil;oise</em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/3Lf3v.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><em>Dessert: Profiteroles</em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/8Gqtt.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I have to begin this post with some apologies. Apologies first to the record collectors who just want to read about the record stores and apologies to non-collectors who may not be interested in such detailed accounts of record stores in Nice. I t...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Tue May 29 15:41:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Tue May 29 15:41:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>134481859</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-5-record-stores-and-more</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
