<item>
	<title>Nice Trip - Day 6: Old Things and Extravagant Dining</title>
	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-6-old-things-and-extravagant-di</link>
	<pubDate>Thu May 31 03:14:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-6-old-things-and-extravagant-di</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for the lateness of this post - the hotel wifi wasn't working last night. I finally found a cafe to write in. Yesterday was a day filled with old things belonging to dead people. The day began at the Mus&eacute;e d'Histoire Naturelle here in Nice. I didn't have many expectations going in, which I guess was good. This museum is <em>tiny</em>. It's really just one room of a few stuffed animals (a lot of birds) and this strange presentation (more on that soon). It was cool, though, to read about the environmental history of the area, and how the environment has changed as cities have grown. This wolf pretty much sums up the animals displayed:</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/sQjuc.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>There was also this strange diorama of two scientists who started discovering wildlife in the area. You press a button and it plays a scene of the two of them talking. The'yre not animatronic, though, there are just spot lights on whoever is talking at a given moment. The preserved animals behind them were kind of cool in a gross way, though. Also, this wasn't a short thing - I stood there for about 10 minutes watching these 2 people talk!</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/tbZFK.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>After the museum, I began wandering a little bit, since I was in a new area. Nothing super exciting - it was a much less touristy area, so there were a lot of normal city things (clothing stores, grocery stores, etc.). I then headed back to that nicer shopping area I mentioned in my last post, to go see what it was all about. In doing so, I stumbled upon the Mus&eacute;e Massena.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Mus&eacute;e Massena used to be a mansion of the Mass&eacute;na family, and was donated by them to become a museum in the early 20th century (just before the first World War). The chateau has been left somewhat the same - it's very extravagant as you might expect and there are big rooms with high ceilings and wall dressings. I especially liked the library and the greatroom. The upstairs is somewhat of a gallery now, and it was really cool to look at the old posters for the festivals they had in Nice. There are also depictions of Nice throughout history, and it was fun to learn about that as well. Outside the museum is a nice garden that I sat in for a while and scribbled in my notebook. Oh yeah, and entrance is free. Score.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/uHMWR.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/XK6Nr.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/qm9aF.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vVCS0.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/5e2wq.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />I've never seen a tiger like this - sad they had to kill such a rare one to become a rug, huh?</p>
<p>After the museum, I headed over to check out the Palais Lascaris, in Vieux Nice. This is an old palace right in the middle of everything (I've walked by it many times and completely missed it). It was converted into a museum in the 60s. The coolest part is the 18th century pharmacy that has been left entirely intact. It reminded me of a scene from <em>Sleep No More</em>. The rest of the palace is an exhibit of instruments from various years, including this funky 19th century upright piano, a cane violin, and serpents.&nbsp;</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/YKiUC.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/T2eIa.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Osok3.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/WaDmJ.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/0cXal.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>And that brings us now to dinner. I figured, since part of this trip is to celebrate my graduation, I should go to one super nice dinner while in Nice. I chose Le Chantecler, which is nestled at the foot of Le Negresco hotel, right on the promenade. Let me give you a taste of what this restaurant is like. The waiters are all dressed in tails. All the silverware, food, drinks, and everything else is served on silver trays, with someone carrying the tray and someone serving it at the table. The dishes are all presented with covers, and all covers at a table are removed at the same time, which became fun to watch at the table next to me, with 10 people, requiring 5 waiters for every course. Among the selections on the menu is a tasting menu, where you simply sit and enjoy 7 courses selected and prepared by the chef. The Menu Chantecler is similar, but with fewer courses, and you pick the main course. I chose to do the Menu Chantecler. Both of these options can also be accompanied by a wine pairing, in case you feel like having 7 glasses of wine with dinner. In short, imagine the most extravagant, fanciest dining experience you can, and then double it. That is the experience of eating at Le Chantecler. Interestingly, the current chef is known for his modern presentations of classic dishes, which adds a subtle reminder that you are, in fact, still in the 21st century. What follows will likely be a long, absurd description, but it is such only to reflect the reality of the meal. I now present Dinner, in 15 movements:</p>
<ol>
<li>I began with the champagne cart - there were three different champagnes to choose from, and they were masterfully poured right there for you.</li>
<li>After the champagne, I was brought the hors d'oeuvres. They were a plate with three little selections. My favorite was the foie gras served on a small chocolate cookie.</li>
<li>I was then presented with, and explained, the menu. The waiter told me about the different dining options, recommended plates, etc.</li>
<li>After some reflection (which is the word used in French when deciding what to eat), I ordered my meal.</li>
<li>I was then told I would be visited next by the Somelier (it's kind of like <em>A Christmas Carol, </em>with more food). He brought me the dictionary-sized binder that is the wine list, and was available for questions while I selected.</li>
<li>I was then presented with the bread options, and picked the olive bread for my first piece. The butter they put at the table was incredible as well.</li>
<li>Next, I was brought a small bowl of soup topped with morels to, as the waiter put it, "give a taste of the chef's cuisine." It was very tasty, especially because I love morels.</li>
<li>Next was a soft egg yolk with green peas cream, served also with meat and salted butter.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/2AJXg.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/jQRt8.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li>
<li>The next dish was lobster meat, served with a red wine sauce and a few vegetables.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/LH11R.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li>
<li>After that, I was brought the dish I had ordered: piglet served with boudin noir, apples and lentils.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/VGaxl.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li>
<li>Next, I was presented with the cheese cart, and told where each of the 10 or so cheeses came from. They all looked incredible. I chose the camembert, the local ch&egrave;vre, and the roquefort. They were served with apricots, figs, and raisin bread.</li>
<li>I was then presented with pre-dessert. What is pre-dessert you ask? It's every child's dream, that's what it is. Pre-dessert was a biscuit and a little bit of vanilla gelato. Very tasty.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/OQkM2.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li>
<li>After pre-dessert, I had dessert. This was swiss chard pie, a local specialty (it is also served as a savory pie), with orange blossom cream and a bit of sorbet.<br /> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/UDQbh.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></li>
<li>After dessert, I was presented with the coffee menu. The restaurant has about 8 different coffees to choose from, and they are all described in detail (including the type of bean and origin), with tasting notes for each.</li>
<li>Lastly, the after-dessert cart was brought over. This was a selection of macaroons, truffles, and other small pastries or candies to select from.</li>
</ol>
<p>After all that, I basically rolled home - there was so much food. The experience was unlike anything I've ever done, and though it was wildly expensive, you receive a lot of amazing food, and it is entirely worth it. I almost instantly passed out from from food overload and slept like a baby, even though Cypress Hill was performing just across the street from my hotel. Another great day on this great voyage.</p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Sorry for the lateness of this post - the hotel wifi wasn't working last night. I finally found a cafe to write in. Yesterday was a day filled with old things belonging to dead people. The day began at the Musée d'Histoire Naturelle here in Nice. ...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Thu May 31 03:14:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Thu May 31 03:14:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>134865262</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-6-old-things-and-extravagant-di</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
