<item>
	<title>Nice Trip - Day 7: I'm near a boat!</title>
	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-7-im-near-a-boat</link>
	<pubDate>Thu May 31 15:35:00 -0700 2012</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="+Travel"><![CDATA[ Travel]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="Nice"><![CDATA[Nice]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/nice-trip-day-7-im-near-a-boat</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today was an especially packed day, filled with a lot of walking. You see, east of Vieux Nice is the port area, which I previously had no real reason to visit (also, it's a far walk, and I like walking). However, I read about the Mus&eacute;e de Terra Amata, which was supposed to be pretty cool, and it's over there, so I decided to go check it out.</p>
<p>But before the museum was the Italian Festival. Right across the street from my hotel, this festival has started. Vendors from Italy bring cheese, meat, bread, oil, wine, etc. from Italy and present it here. I think it's the first time that they've had it, and it's pretty cool. There are a lot of free samples, and I managed to basically eat a meal for free just wandering around. Notable sights include huge blocks of cheese that I thought were bread until I smelled them, giant blocks of prosciutto, and whole truffles (which I had never seen before). Entrance is free, too! There are two places offering porchetta, which I've wanted to try for a long time, so lunch tomorrow will be there for sure (I wasn't hungry after all the sampling today).</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/okTjy.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2vQqX.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Cheese, disguised as bread</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/nq7My.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Actual bread</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2oHRT.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/u05GE.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Truffles. Mmm.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/QUezX.jpg" alt="" width="450" /><br />Do you think they'd let me take this on the plane as my "personal item"?</p>
<p>After checking out the festival, I headed over to the museum. The walk was long, but along the beach so it was nice (it also wasn't too hot today). Along the way, I found this human sundial. You stand on the marker and it will tell you what time it is! It's pre-DST, though, so it was an hour off.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/MuTaU.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>The Terra Amata museum itself is small (noticing a theme here?), but was still pretty cool. The main attraction is this giant fossil platform they dug up on the beach, with lots of fossils in it, including the oldest know human foot print! Upstairs were other local fossils of humans and animals, as well as ancient tools. It presents an ancient history of the Nice area, and how they used the beach, the animals, and the environment. They also have a recreation of a hut that was on the beach and that was used as living quarters.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/OXmCM.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/FbjwH.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/h2qfL.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>After the museum, I wandered a bit around the harbor area. There's not a lot around there (a bunch of restaurants along the water, though), but there is a theater if you want to find out when to see plays, and an area full of antique stores. Most of the stores are high-end antiques: tables, paintings, large elephant sculptures, things of that sort. If you're interested more in trinkets (aka me), the place to go is Les Puces de Nice. It's a small antique market that's similar to the one at Cours Selaya, but much much smaller. Still, there are a fair number of vendors there and some cool stuff. The layout and the enclosed nature of the market reminded me of the market in NYC near Astor Place that was tented in on a lot off the street (I'm not sure if it exists anymore), but of much higher quality. Definitely check this market out.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/UsLom.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2DA92.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>After some more wandering and scenery gazing (because it's important to appreciate the beauty of where you are), I headed back to my hotel to relax and soak my feet. For dinner, I was in the mood for seafood, so I headed back towards the harbor and came across Le Lunel, a restaurant right on the harbor. I started with the fish soup, which was basically like bouillabaisse lite, and very tasty. Next I had black pollock, which I had never had or heard of as far as I know. It was also very good. I finished with tiramisu, which was really quite good; it had a nice coffee flavor and wasn't too mushy (the layers were distinct). I also had beer instead of wine because I haven't had much beer while I was here, and the wine choices didn't really interest me.</p>
<p><em>First Course: Soupe de poisson</em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/UzTkz.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><em>Second Course: Filet de lieu au safran</em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/RHlrv.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p><em>Dessert: Tiramisu</em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/O7I9Q.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>After dinner, I stopped by the Arts and Crafts market at Cours Selaya, which just started tonight. This market runs every night (6pm to midnight) except Mondays until September. I had heard it didn't start until tomorrow, but as I was walking along the promenade, some shiny jewelry caught my eye and I went to inspect. Cours Selaya at night is usually dedicated to the restaurants, they add tables to the middle where the day's market normally is, so the crafts market finds itself filling in the gaps, which adds an interesting dynamic. It took a lot of energy not to stand next to someone's dinner table, inspecting as if I was still looking at a table of wares. The stands are, for the most part, local residents selling their creations. There is a lot of jewelry, but also other handmade items, like bags, paintings, wooden puzzles and games, stauettes, and even beautiful handmade marble moartar and pestles. I always like supporting local artists whenever I can, as well as asking whoever made an item for details about it, so it was fun to browse and inspect.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ThsfG.jpg" alt="" width="450" /></p>
<p>I headed back to my hotel, happy of my walk back, and it wasn't long until I started hearing loud explosions. There was a fireworks show originating out in the sea. I'm not sure what the occasion was, but it was certainly fun to watch the end of.</p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Today was an especially packed day, filled with a lot of walking. You see, east of Vieux Nice is the port area, which I previously had no real reason to visit (also, it's a far walk, and I like walking). However, I read about the Musée de Terra Am...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Thu May 31 15:35:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Thu May 31 15:35:00 -0700 2012</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>134997614</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>nice-trip-day-7-im-near-a-boat</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
