<item>
	<title>Recipe: Slow Cooker Chili</title>
	<link>http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/recipe-slow-cooker-chili</link>
	<pubDate>Sun Oct 02 17:24:00 -0700 2011</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Diggs]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="cooking"><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gordondiggs.posterous.com/recipe-slow-cooker-chili</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In my house, there are 5 of us &ndash; we each take turn cooking one night per week. A few weeks ago, I decided to make chili. My housemates and I are all about the heat, so I really wanted to make something with some kick. The following is based very heavily on <a href="http://www.tasteofhome.com/Recipes/Spicy-Slow-Cooked-Chili">this recipe</a>. I didn&rsquo;t manage to catch a photo of it, but it was super tasty and pretty hot (though not unmanageably so). Enjoy!</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>2 pounds ground beef</li>
<li>3 (mostly) seeded habaneros</li>
<li>3 cans (16 ounces each) kidney beans, rinsed and drained</li>
<li>1 can (6 ounces) tomato paste</li>
<li>1 medium onion, chopped</li>
<li>1 poblano pepper, seeded and diced</li>
<li>2 teaspoons chili powder</li>
<li>2 teaspoons cider vinegar</li>
<li>1 teaspoon garlic powder</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dried oregano</li>
<li>&frac12; teaspoon ground cinnamon</li>
<li>&frac14; teaspoon pepper</li>
<li>3 cups tomato juice</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Brown beef in a large skillet and drain. Transfer meat to slow cooker.</li>
<li>Add all other ingredients and mix.</li>
<li>Set the slow cooker to low. Cook for 5 hours.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Notes</h2>

<p>As you can see, this is a super easy chili to make. You can adjust the heat to your liking. And as always, be careful when handling those habaneros &ndash; capsaicin will hurt you.</p>

<hr />

<p>Chez moi, il y a 5 gens. Nous cuisinons à tour de rôle un jour par semaine. Il y a des semaines, j'ai décidé à faire du chili. Mes amis et moi aiment le goût épicé, et j'ai vraiment voulu faire quelque chose avec un &ldquo;recul.&rdquo; Ce qui suit est fondé sur <a href="http://www.tasteofhome.com/Recipes/Spicy-Slow-Cooked-Chili">cette recette</a>. Je n'ai pas pris un photo du chili, mais c'était delicieux et très épicé (mais pas trop).</p>

<h2>Ingrédients</h2>

<ul>
<li>2 livres de boeuf</li>
<li>3 habaneros, épépinés</li>
<li>3 16oz boites des haricots rouge</li>
<li>1 6oz boite de la pâte des tomates</li>
<li>1 oignon moyen, émincé</li>
<li>1 poplano, épépiné et coupé</li>
<li>2 cuillères à thé de la poudre de chili</li>
<li>2 cuillères à thé du vinaigre de cidre</li>
<li>1 cuillère à thé de l'ail en poudre</li>
<li>1 cuillère à thé de l'origan sec</li>
<li>&frac12; cuillère à thé de la cannelle en poudre</li>
<li>&frac14; cuillère à thé du poivre</li>
<li>3 tasses du jus du tomate</li>
</ul>


<h2>Instructions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Faites dorer la boeuf et la faites dégorger. Mettez la boeuf dans une cocotte.</li>
<li>Ajoutez les autres ingrédients et les mélangez.</li>
<li>Cuisinez à feu doux pour 5 heures.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Notes</h2>

<p>Ce chili est super facile à préparer. On peut changer les piments à la choix. Comme toujours, faites attention avec les habaneros &ndash; le capsaicin est dangereux.</p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In my house, there are 5 of us – we each take turn cooking one night per week. A few weeks ago, I decided to make chili. My housemates and I are all about the heat, so I really wanted to make something with some kick. The following is based very...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Sun Oct 02 17:24:00 -0700 2011</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sun Oct 02 17:24:00 -0700 2011</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>73660947</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>recipe-slow-cooker-chili</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
